# idx	form	lemma	pos	ne	head	deprel	label

0	In	in	IN	O	4	case	-
1	1832	1832	CD	DATE	4	nummod	-
2	his	he	PRP$	O	4	nmod:poss	-
3	family	family	NN	O	5	nmod	0
4	emigrated	emigrate	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
5	thence	thence	RB	O	5	advmod	1
6	to	to	TO	O	8	case	-
7	Belleville	Belleville	NNP	LOCATION	6	nmod	-
8	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
9	Ontario	Ontario	NNP	LOCATION	8	appos	-
10	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
11	where	where	WRB	O	14	advmod	-
12	he	he	PRP	O	14	nsubj	-
13	apprenticed	apprentice	VBD	O	5	advcl	0
14	with	with	IN	O	17	case	-
15	the	the	DT	O	17	det	-
16	printer	printer	NN	O	14	nmod	0
17	at	at	IN	O	21	case	-
18	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
19	town	town	NN	O	21	compound	0
20	newspaper	newspaper	NN	O	14	nmod	0
21	,	,	,	O	14	punct	-
22	The	the	DT	O	25	det	-
23	Belleville	Belleville	NNP	LOCATION	25	compound	-
24	Intelligencer	Intelligencer	NNP	LOCATION	14	dobj	-
25	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Leo	Leo	NNP	PERSON	7	nsubj	-
1	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
2	on	on	IN	O	4	case	-
3	December	December	NNP	DATE	7	nmod	-
4	23	23	CD	DATE	4	nummod	-
5	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
6	took	take	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
7	an	a	DT	O	9	det	-
8	oath	oath	NN	O	7	dobj	0
9	of	of	IN	O	11	case	-
10	purgation	purgation	NN	O	9	nmod	1
11	concerning	concern	VBG	O	14	case	0
12	the	the	DT	O	14	det	-
13	charges	charge	NNS	O	9	nmod	0
14	brought	bring	VBN	O	14	acl	0
15	against	against	IN	O	17	case	-
16	him	he	PRP	O	15	nmod	-
17	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
18	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	-
19	his	he	PRP$	O	21	nmod:poss	-
20	opponents	opponent	NNS	O	23	nsubjpass	0
21	were	be	VBD	O	23	auxpass	0
22	exiled	exile	VBN	O	7	conj	0
23	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	During	during	IN	O	3	case	-
1	the	the	DT	O	3	det	-
2	attack	attack	NN	O	19	nmod	0
3	,	,	,	O	19	punct	-
4	a	a	DT	O	6	det	-
5	blast	blast	NN	O	19	nsubjpass	0
6	from	from	IN	O	9	case	-
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	-
8	explosion	explosion	NN	O	6	nmod	0
9	of	of	IN	O	11	case	-
10	gunpowder	gunpowder	NN	O	9	nmod	0
11	stored	store	VBN	O	11	acl	0
12	in	in	IN	O	17	case	-
13	Captain	Captain	NNP	O	15	compound	-
14	Jacobs	Jacobs	NNP	PERSON	17	nmod:poss	-
15	's	's	POS	O	15	case	-
16	house	house	NN	O	12	nmod	0
17	was	be	VBD	O	19	auxpass	0
18	heard	hear	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
19	in	in	IN	O	21	case	-
20	Pittsburgh	Pittsburgh	NNP	LOCATION	19	nmod	-
21	,	,	,	O	21	punct	-
22	44	44	CD	NUMBER	24	nummod	-
23	miles	mile	NNS	O	25	nmod:npmod	0
24	away	away	RB	O	21	advmod	1
25	.	.	.	O	19	punct	-

0	Although	although	IN	O	6	mark	-
1	anoxic	anoxic	JJ	O	3	amod	1
2	events	event	NNS	O	6	nsubj	0
3	have	have	VBP	O	6	aux	1
4	not	not	RB	O	6	neg	0
5	happened	happen	VBN	O	15	advcl	0
6	for	for	IN	O	8	case	-
7	millions	million	NNS	DURATION	6	nmod	0
8	of	of	IN	DURATION	10	case	-
9	years	year	NNS	DURATION	8	nmod	0
10	,	,	,	O	15	punct	-
11	the	the	DT	O	14	det	-
12	geological	geological	JJ	O	14	amod	0
13	record	record	NN	O	15	nsubj	0
14	shows	show	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
15	that	that	IN	O	18	mark	-
16	they	they	PRP	O	18	nsubj	-
17	happened	happen	VBD	O	15	ccomp	0
18	many	many	JJ	O	20	amod	-
19	times	time	NNS	O	18	nmod:tmod	0
20	in	in	IN	O	23	case	-
21	the	the	DT	DATE	23	det	-
22	past	past	NN	DATE	18	nmod	0
23	.	.	.	O	15	punct	-

0	It	it	PRP	O	4	nsubj	-
1	just	just	RB	O	3	advmod	0
2	so	so	RB	O	4	advmod	0
3	happens	happen	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
4	in	in	IN	O	7	case	-
5	this	this	DT	O	7	det	-
6	batch	batch	NN	O	12	nmod	0
7	of	of	IN	O	9	case	-
8	songs	song	NNS	O	7	nmod	0
9	I	I	PRP	O	12	nsubj	-
10	would	would	MD	O	12	aux	-
11	look	look	VB	O	4	ccomp	0
12	at	at	IN	O	15	case	-
13	these	these	DT	O	15	det	-
14	subjects	subject	NNS	O	12	nmod	0
15	and	and	CC	O	12	cc	-
16	thought	think	VBD	O	12	conj	0
17	it	it	PRP	O	20	nsubj	-
18	was	be	VBD	O	20	cop	0
19	good	good	JJ	O	17	ccomp	0
20	for	for	IN	O	22	mark	-
21	writing	write	VBG	O	20	advcl	0
22	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	name	name	NN	O	7	nsubj	0
2	``	``	``	O	5	punct	-
3	kangaroo	kangaroo	NN	O	5	compound	0
4	mouse	mouse	NN	O	2	appos	0
5	''	''	''	O	5	punct	-
6	refers	refer	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
7	to	to	TO	O	14	case	-
8	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
9	species	species	NNS	O	14	nmod:poss	0
10	'	'	POS	O	10	case	-
11	extraordinary	extraordinary	JJ	O	14	amod	0
12	jumping	jump	VBG	O	14	amod	0
13	ability	ability	NN	O	7	nmod	0
14	,	,	,	O	14	punct	-
15	as	as	RB	O	14	cc	-
16	well	well	RB	O	16	mwe	-
17	as	as	IN	O	16	mwe	-
18	its	its	PRP$	O	20	nmod:poss	-
19	habit	habit	NN	O	14	conj	0
20	of	of	IN	O	23	case	-
21	bipedal	bipedal	JJ	O	23	amod	1
22	locomotion	locomotion	NN	O	20	nmod	0
23	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	burrow	burrow	NN	O	17	nsubjpass	0
2	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
3	the	the	DT	O	5	det	-
4	entrance	entrance	NN	O	2	appos	0
5	to	to	TO	O	7	case	-
6	which	which	WDT	O	10	nmod	-
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	-
8	mouse	mouse	NN	O	10	nsubj	0
9	covers	cover	VBZ	O	5	acl:relcl	0
10	during	during	IN	O	13	case	-
11	daylight	daylight	NN	TIME	13	compound	0
12	hours	hour	NNS	DURATION	10	nmod	0
13	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
14	is	be	VBZ	O	17	auxpass	0
15	also	also	RB	O	17	advmod	0
16	used	use	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
17	to	to	TO	O	19	mark	-
18	raise	raise	VB	O	17	xcomp	0
19	litters	litter	NNS	O	19	dobj	0
20	of	of	IN	O	26	case	-
21	between	between	IN	O	26	case	-
22	2	2	CD	NUMBER	26	nummod	-
23	and	and	CC	NUMBER	23	cc	-
24	7	7	CD	NUMBER	23	conj	-
25	young	young	JJ	O	20	nmod	0
26	.	.	.	O	17	punct	-

0	Midway	Midway	NNP	O	9	dep	-
1	through	through	IN	O	5	case	-
2	the	the	DT	O	5	det	-
3	1992	1992	CD	DATE	5	nummod	-
4	season	season	NN	O	1	nmod	0
5	,	,	,	O	1	punct	-
6	the	the	DT	O	8	det	-
7	team	team	NN	O	9	nsubj	0
8	collapsed	collapse	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
9	financially	financially	RB	O	9	advmod	0
10	as	as	IN	O	14	mark	-
11	Middlebridge	middlebridge	NN	LOCATION	14	nsubj	-
12	was	be	VBD	O	14	cop	0
13	unable	unable	JJ	O	9	advcl	0
14	to	to	TO	O	16	mark	-
15	make	make	VB	O	14	xcomp	0
16	repayments	repayment	NNS	O	16	dobj	0
17	against	against	IN	O	19	case	-
18	loans	loan	NNS	O	17	nmod	1
19	provided	provide	VBN	O	19	acl	0
20	by	by	IN	O	23	case	-
21	Landhurst	Landhurst	NNP	ORGANIZATION	23	compound	-
22	Leasing	Leasing	NNP	ORGANIZATION	20	nmod	-
23	.	.	.	O	9	punct	-

0	During	during	IN	O	3	case	-
1	this	this	DT	O	3	det	-
2	period	period	NN	O	9	nmod	0
3	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
4	teams	team	NNS	O	9	nsubj	0
5	using	use	VBG	O	5	acl	0
6	Brabham	Brabham	NNP	PERSON	8	compound	-
7	cars	car	NNS	O	6	dobj	0
8	won	win	VBD	O	0	ROOT	1
9	championships	championship	NNS	O	9	dobj	0
10	in	in	IN	O	12	case	-
11	Formula	Formula	NNP	MISC	10	nmod	-
12	Two	two	CD	NUMBER	12	nummod	-
13	and	and	CC	O	12	cc	-
14	Formula	Formula	NNP	O	16	compound	-
15	Three	three	CD	NUMBER	12	conj	-
16	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
17	competed	compete	VBD	O	9	conj	0
18	in	in	IN	O	22	case	-
19	the	the	DT	O	22	det	-
20	Indianapolis	Indianapolis	NNP	LOCATION	22	compound	-
21	500	500	CD	NUMBER	18	nmod	-
22	.	.	.	O	9	punct	-

0	Their	they	PRP$	O	5	nmod:poss	-
1	thick	thick	JJ	O	5	amod	0
2	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
3	shimmery	shimmery	JJ	O	5	amod	0
4	fur	fur	NN	O	6	nsubj	0
5	sparkles	sparkle	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
6	with	with	IN	O	9	case	-
7	tiny	tiny	JJ	O	9	amod	0
8	lights	light	NNS	O	6	nmod	0
9	;	;	:	O	6	punct	-
10	their	they	PRP$	O	15	nmod:poss	-
11	Kewpie	Kewpie	NNP	O	15	compound	-
12	doll	doll	NN	O	15	compound	0
13	style	style	NN	O	15	compound	0
14	heads	head	NNS	O	17	nsubj	0
15	are	be	VBP	O	17	cop	0
16	hairless	hairless	JJ	O	6	parataxis	0
17	and	and	CC	O	17	cc	-
18	feature	feature	NN	O	21	compound	0
19	big	big	JJ	O	21	amod	0
20	eyes	eye	NNS	O	17	conj	0
21	with	with	IN	O	23	case	-
22	rows	row	NNS	O	21	nmod	0
23	of	of	IN	O	25	case	-
24	lights	light	NNS	O	23	nmod	0
25	for	for	IN	O	27	case	-
26	eyebrows	eyebrow	NNS	O	25	nmod	0
27	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	4	det	-
1	Pale	Pale	NNP	O	4	compound	-
2	Kangaroo	Kangaroo	NNP	O	4	compound	-
3	Mouse	Mouse	NNP	O	5	nsubj	-
4	burrows	burrow	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
5	only	only	RB	O	9	advmod	0
6	in	in	IN	O	9	case	-
7	fine	fine	JJ	O	9	amod	0
8	sand	sand	NN	O	5	nmod	0
9	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
10	while	while	IN	O	16	mark	-
11	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
12	Dark	dark	JJ	O	15	amod	-
13	Kangaroo	Kangaroo	NNP	O	15	compound	-
14	Mouse	Mouse	NNP	O	16	nsubj	-
15	prefers	prefer	VBZ	O	5	advcl	0
16	fine	fine	JJ	O	20	amod	0
17	,	,	,	O	17	punct	-
18	gravelly	gravelly	JJ	O	20	amod	0
19	soils	soil	NNS	O	16	dobj	0
20	but	but	CC	O	16	cc	-
21	may	may	MD	O	24	aux	-
22	also	also	RB	O	24	advmod	0
23	burrow	burrow	VB	O	16	conj	1
24	in	in	IN	O	26	case	-
25	sand	sand	NN	O	24	nmod	0
26	or	or	CC	O	26	cc	-
27	sandy	sandy	JJ	O	29	amod	0
28	soil	soil	NN	O	26	conj	0
29	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Theobroma	Theobroma	NNP	O	2	compound	-
1	species	species	NNS	O	4	nsubjpass	0
2	are	be	VBP	O	4	auxpass	0
3	used	use	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
4	as	as	IN	O	7	case	-
5	food	food	NN	O	7	compound	0
6	plants	plant	NNS	O	4	nmod	0
7	by	by	IN	O	10	case	-
8	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
9	larvae	larva	NNS	O	4	nmod	0
10	of	of	IN	O	13	case	-
11	some	some	DT	O	13	det	-
12	moths	moth	NNS	O	10	nmod	1
13	of	of	IN	O	17	case	-
14	the	the	DT	O	17	det	-
15	genus	genus	NN	O	17	compound	0
16	Endoclita	endoclita	NN	O	13	nmod	-
17	including	include	VBG	O	20	case	0
18	E.	E.	NNP	MISC	20	compound	-
19	chalybeatus	chalybeatus	NN	O	17	nmod	1
20	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
21	E.	E.	NNP	O	23	compound	-
22	damor	damor	NNP	O	20	conj	1
23	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
24	E.	E.	NNP	O	26	compound	-
25	hosei	hoseus	NNS	O	20	conj	1
26	and	and	CC	O	20	cc	-
27	E.	E.	NNP	O	29	compound	-
28	sericeus	sericeus	NN	O	20	conj	0
29	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	Some	some	DT	O	2	det	-
1	examples	example	NNS	O	3	nsubj	0
2	include	include	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
3	Franklin	Franklin	NNP	ORGANIZATION	3	dobj	-
4	from	from	IN	O	6	case	-
5	Canada	Canada	NNP	LOCATION	4	nmod	-
6	and	and	CC	O	6	cc	-
7	Tweenies	Tweenies	NNP	LOCATION	6	conj	-
8	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
9	Connie	Connie	NNP	MISC	12	compound	-
10	the	the	DT	MISC	12	det	-
11	Cow	cow	NN	MISC	4	appos	-
12	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
13	Tiny	Tiny	NNP	O	15	compound	-
14	Planets	Planets	NNPS	O	4	appos	-
15	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
16	and	and	CC	O	4	cc	-
17	64	64	CD	NUMBER	20	nummod	-
18	Zoo	zoo	NN	O	20	compound	-
19	Lane	Lane	NNP	O	4	conj	-
20	from	from	IN	O	23	case	-
21	the	the	DT	O	23	det	-
22	UK	UK	NNP	LOCATION	4	nmod	-
23	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	-
1	1756	1756	CD	DATE	7	nmod	-
2	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
3	the	the	DT	O	5	det	-
4	village	village	NN	O	7	nsubjpass	0
5	was	be	VBD	O	7	auxpass	0
6	destroyed	destroy	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
7	by	by	IN	O	10	case	-
8	John	John	NNP	PERSON	10	compound	-
9	Armstrong	Armstrong	NNP	PERSON	7	nmod	-
10	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
11	Sr.	Sr.	NNP	O	10	appos	-
12	at	at	IN	O	15	case	-
13	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
14	Battle	battle	NN	O	12	nmod	-
15	of	of	IN	O	17	case	-
16	Kittanning	Kittanning	NNP	LOCATION	15	nmod	-
17	during	during	IN	O	23	case	-
18	the	the	DT	O	23	det	-
19	French	french	JJ	MISC	23	amod	0
20	and	and	CC	O	20	cc	-
21	Indian	indian	JJ	MISC	20	conj	-
22	War	war	NN	MISC	15	nmod	-
23	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	band	band	NN	O	5	nsubjpass	0
2	was	be	VBD	O	5	auxpass	0
3	officially	officially	RB	O	5	advmod	0
4	formed	form	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	in	in	IN	O	7	case	-
6	1999	1999	CD	DATE	5	nmod	-
7	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
8	known	know	VBN	O	7	acl	0
9	at	at	IN	O	12	case	-
10	that	that	DT	O	12	det	-
11	time	time	NN	O	9	nmod	0
12	as	as	IN	O	14	case	-
13	Imagica	Imagica	NNP	PERSON	12	nmod	-
14	,	,	,	O	14	punct	-
15	a	a	DT	O	17	det	-
16	name	name	NN	O	14	appos	0
17	taken	take	VBN	O	17	acl	0
18	from	from	IN	O	21	case	-
19	a	a	DT	O	21	det	-
20	novel	novel	JJ	O	18	nmod	0
21	by	by	IN	O	24	case	-
22	Clive	Clive	NNP	PERSON	24	compound	-
23	Barker	Barker	NNP	PERSON	18	nmod	-
24	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	It	it	PRP	O	2	nsubj	-
1	resembles	resemble	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
2	five	five	CD	NUMBER	5	nummod	-
3	deep	deep	JJ	O	5	amod	0
4	spoons	spoon	NNS	O	2	dobj	0
5	with	with	IN	O	8	case	-
6	the	the	DT	O	8	det	-
7	handles	handle	VBZ	O	5	nmod	0
8	linked	link	VBN	O	8	acl	0
9	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
10	or	or	CC	O	9	cc	-
11	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
12	alternately	alternately	RB	O	9	conj	0
13	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
15	hammocks	hammock	NNS	O	17	nsubj	0
16	resemble	resemble	VBP	O	9	parataxis	0
17	five	five	CD	NUMBER	20	nummod	-
18	fig	fig	JJ	O	20	amod	0
19	halves	half	NNS	O	17	dobj	0
20	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	energy	energy	NN	O	4	nsubjpass	0
2	is	be	VBZ	O	4	auxpass	0
3	created	create	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
4	by	by	IN	O	7	case	-
5	the	the	DT	O	7	det	-
6	laughter	laughter	NN	O	4	nmod	0
7	of	of	IN	O	10	case	-
8	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
9	children	child	NNS	O	7	nmod	0
10	when	when	WRB	O	12	advmod	-
11	playing	play	VBG	O	4	advcl	0
12	with	with	IN	O	15	case	-
13	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
14	Boohbahs	Boohbahs	NNP	PERSON	12	nmod	-
15	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
16	the	the	DT	O	18	det	-
17	Boohball	Boohball	NNP	PERSON	16	root	-
18	,	,	,	O	18	punct	-
19	and	and	CC	O	18	cc	-
20	the	the	DT	O	22	det	-
21	Storypeople	Storypeople	NNP	O	18	conj	-
22	.	.	.	O	18	punct	-

0	He	he	PRP	O	5	nsubjpass	-
1	is	be	VBZ	O	5	auxpass	0
2	probably	probably	RB	O	5	advmod	0
3	best	best	RB	O	5	advmod	0
4	known	know	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	for	for	IN	O	7	mark	-
6	hosting	host	VBG	O	5	advcl	0
7	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
8	game	game	NN	O	10	compound	0
9	show	show	NN	O	7	dobj	0
10	Trash	trash	NN	MISC	10	dep	-
11	to	to	TO	O	13	case	-
12	Treasure	treasure	NN	O	11	nmod	-
13	and	and	CC	O	13	cc	-
14	his	he	PRP$	O	16	nmod:poss	-
15	role	role	NN	O	13	conj	0
16	as	as	IN	O	19	case	-
17	``	``	``	O	19	punct	-
18	Dude	Dude	NNP	O	11	nmod	0
19	''	''	''	O	19	punct	-
20	in	in	IN	O	26	case	-
21	The	the	DT	O	23	det	-
22	N	n	NN	O	26	nmod:poss	-
23	's	's	POS	O	23	case	-
24	television	television	NN	O	26	compound	0
25	series	series	NN	O	19	nmod	0
26	About	about	IN	O	29	case	-
27	a	a	DT	O	29	det	-
28	Girl	Girl	NNP	O	26	nmod	-
29	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Sandy	Sandy	NNP	PERSON	3	nsubj	0
1	has	have	VBZ	O	3	aux	0
2	starred	star	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
3	in	in	IN	O	7	case	-
4	many	many	JJ	O	7	amod	-
5	theatrical	theatrical	JJ	O	7	amod	0
6	productions	production	NNS	O	3	nmod	0
7	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
8	including	include	VBG	O	13	case	0
9	the	the	DT	O	13	det	-
10	one	one	CD	NUMBER	13	nummod	0
11	man	man	NN	O	13	compound	0
12	show	show	NN	O	7	nmod	0
13	Full	full	JJ	O	15	amod	-
14	Committed	commit	VBN	O	13	dep	-
15	,	,	,	O	15	punct	-
16	in	in	IN	O	18	case	-
17	which	which	WDT	O	20	nmod	-
18	he	he	PRP	O	20	nsubj	-
19	played	play	VBD	O	15	acl:relcl	0
20	40	40	CD	NUMBER	22	nummod	-
21	characters	character	NNS	O	20	dobj	0
22	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	Fish	fish	NN	O	9	nsubj	0
1	and	and	CC	O	1	cc	-
2	copra	copra	NN	O	1	conj	0
3	are	be	VBP	O	9	cop	0
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	country	country	NN	O	9	nmod:poss	0
6	's	's	POS	O	6	case	-
7	major	major	JJ	O	9	amod	0
8	exports	export	NNS	O	0	ROOT	0
9	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
10	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
11	cotton	cotton	NN	O	13	compound	0
12	goods	goods	NNS	O	25	nsubj	0
13	,	,	,	O	13	punct	-
14	motor	motor	NN	O	16	compound	0
15	vehicles	vehicle	NNS	O	13	conj	0
16	,	,	,	O	13	punct	-
17	meats	meat	NNS	O	13	conj	0
18	,	,	,	O	13	punct	-
19	and	and	CC	O	13	cc	-
20	sugar	sugar	NN	O	13	conj	0
21	are	be	VBP	O	25	cop	0
22	the	the	DT	O	25	det	-
23	major	major	JJ	O	25	amod	0
24	imports	import	NNS	O	9	conj	0
25	.	.	.	O	9	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	-
1	common	common	JJ	O	24	advcl	0
2	with	with	IN	O	7	case	-
3	all	all	DT	O	7	det	-
4	London	London	NNP	LOCATION	7	compound	-
5	transport	transport	NN	O	7	compound	0
6	authorities	authority	NNS	O	2	nmod	0
7	from	from	IN	O	9	case	-
8	1933	1933	CD	DATE	7	nmod	-
9	to	to	TO	DATE	11	dep	-
10	2000	2000	CD	DATE	9	nmod	-
11	,	,	,	O	24	punct	-
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
13	public	public	JJ	O	15	amod	0
14	name	name	NN	O	24	nsubj	0
15	and	and	CC	O	15	cc	-
16	operational	operational	JJ	O	18	amod	0
17	brand	brand	NN	O	15	conj	0
18	of	of	IN	O	21	case	-
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	organization	organization	NN	O	15	nmod	0
21	was	be	VBD	O	24	cop	0
22	London	London	NNP	ORGANIZATION	24	compound	-
23	Transport	Transport	NNP	ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT	-
24	.	.	.	O	24	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	structure	structure	NN	O	4	nsubjpass	0
2	is	be	VBZ	O	4	auxpass	0
3	known	know	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
4	as	as	IN	O	8	case	-
5	the	the	DT	O	8	det	-
6	middle	middle	JJ	O	8	amod	0
7	ear	ear	NN	O	4	nmod	0
8	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
9	and	and	CC	O	4	cc	-
10	is	be	VBZ	O	12	auxpass	0
11	made	make	VBN	O	4	conj	0
12	up	up	RP	O	12	compound:prt	-
13	of	of	IN	O	16	case	-
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
15	incus	incus	NN	O	12	nmod	1
16	,	,	,	O	16	punct	-
17	stapes	stape	NNS	O	16	conj	1
18	,	,	,	O	16	punct	-
19	malleus	malleus	NN	O	16	conj	1
20	,	,	,	O	16	punct	-
21	and	and	CC	O	16	cc	-
22	tympanic	tympanic	JJ	O	24	amod	1
23	membrane	membrane	NN	O	16	conj	0
24	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	Doctors	doctor	NNS	O	2	nsubj	0
1	recommend	recommend	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
2	that	that	IN	O	20	mark	-
3	women	woman	NNS	O	20	nsubj	0
4	over	over	IN	O	6	case	-
5	30	30	CD	NUMBER	4	nmod	-
6	who	who	WP	O	10	nsubj	-
7	have	have	VBP	O	10	aux	0
8	been	be	VBN	O	10	cop	0
9	unsuccessful	unsuccessful	JJ	O	6	acl:relcl	0
10	in	in	IN	O	12	mark	-
11	trying	try	VBG	O	10	advcl	0
12	to	to	TO	O	14	mark	-
13	conceive	conceive	VB	O	12	xcomp	0
14	for	for	IN	O	19	case	-
15	more	more	JJR	DURATION	18	advmod	0
16	than	than	IN	DURATION	16	mwe	-
17	6	6	CD	DURATION	19	nummod	-
18	months	month	NNS	DURATION	14	nmod	0
19	undergo	undergo	VBP	O	2	ccomp	1
20	some	some	DT	O	22	det	-
21	kind	kind	NN	O	20	dobj	0
22	of	of	IN	O	25	case	-
23	fertility	fertility	NN	O	25	compound	0
24	testing	testing	NN	O	22	nmod	0
25	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	Twenty-six	twenty-six	CD	NUMBER	7	nsubjpass	-
1	of	of	IN	O	5	case	-
2	these	these	DT	O	5	det	-
3	0-6-0	0-6-0	CD	NUMBER	5	nummod	-
4	locomotives	locomotive	NNS	O	1	nmod	0
5	were	be	VBD	O	7	auxpass	0
6	ordered	order	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
7	in	in	IN	O	9	case	-
8	January	January	NNP	DATE	7	nmod	-
9	1963	1963	CD	DATE	9	nummod	-
10	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
11	to	to	TO	O	14	mark	-
12	be	be	VB	O	14	auxpass	0
13	built	build	VBN	O	7	xcomp	0
14	at	at	IN	O	19	case	-
15	British	british	JJ	ORGANIZATION	19	amod	-
16	Railways	Railways	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	19	compound	-
17	Swindon	Swindon	NNP	ORGANIZATION	19	compound	-
18	Works	Works	NNP	ORGANIZATION	14	nmod	-
19	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	Later	later	RB	O	3	advmod	0
1	in	in	IN	O	3	case	-
2	development	development	NN	O	8	nmod	0
3	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
4	the	the	DT	O	7	det	-
5	bone	bone	NN	O	7	compound	0
6	structure	structure	NN	O	8	nsubj	0
7	breaks	break	NNS	O	0	ROOT	0
8	loose	loose	RB	O	8	advmod	0
9	from	from	IN	O	12	case	-
10	the	the	DT	O	12	det	-
11	jaw	jaw	NN	O	8	nmod	0
12	and	and	CC	O	8	cc	-
13	migrates	migrate	VBZ	O	8	conj	0
14	to	to	TO	O	19	case	-
15	the	the	DT	O	19	det	-
16	inner	inner	JJ	O	19	amod	0
17	ear	ear	NN	O	19	compound	0
18	area	area	NN	O	14	nmod	0
19	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	-
1	March	March	NNP	DATE	10	nmod	-
2	1992	1992	CD	DATE	2	nummod	-
3	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
4	Linux	Linux	NNP	O	6	compound	-
5	version	version	NN	O	10	nsubj	0
6	0.95	0.95	CD	NUMBER	6	nummod	-
7	was	be	VBD	O	10	cop	0
8	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
9	first	first	JJ	ORDINAL	23	csubj	0
10	to	to	TO	O	13	mark	-
11	be	be	VB	O	13	cop	0
12	capable	capable	JJ	O	10	xcomp	0
13	of	of	IN	O	15	mark	-
14	running	run	VBG	O	13	advcl	0
15	X.	X.	NNP	O	21	compound	-
16	This	this	DT	O	21	det	-
17	large	large	JJ	O	21	amod	0
18	version	version	NN	O	21	compound	0
19	number	number	NN	O	21	compound	0
20	jump	jump	NN	O	15	dobj	0
21	was	be	VBD	O	23	cop	0
22	due	due	JJ	O	0	ROOT	0
23	to	to	TO	O	26	case	-
24	a	a	DT	O	26	det	-
25	feeling	feeling	NN	O	23	nmod	0
26	that	that	IN	O	37	mark	-
27	a	a	DT	O	29	det	-
28	version	version	NN	O	37	nsubj	0
29	1.0	1.0	CD	NUMBER	29	nummod	-
30	with	with	IN	O	35	case	-
31	no	no	DT	O	35	neg	-
32	major	major	JJ	O	35	amod	0
33	missing	miss	VBG	O	35	amod	0
34	pieces	piece	NNS	O	29	nmod	0
35	was	be	VBD	O	37	cop	0
36	imminent	imminent	JJ	O	26	ccomp	0
37	.	.	.	O	23	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	United	United	NNP	LOCATION	3	compound	-
2	States	States	NNPS	LOCATION	4	nsubj	-
3	convened	convene	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
4	a	a	DT	O	7	det	-
5	13-nation	13-nation	JJ	O	7	amod	-
6	conference	conference	NN	O	4	dobj	0
7	of	of	IN	O	12	case	-
8	the	the	DT	O	12	det	-
9	International	International	NNP	ORGANIZATION	12	compound	-
10	Opium	Opium	NNP	ORGANIZATION	12	compound	-
11	Commission	Commission	NNP	ORGANIZATION	7	nmod	-
12	in	in	IN	O	14	case	-
13	1909	1909	CD	DATE	7	nmod	-
14	in	in	IN	O	16	case	-
15	Shanghai	Shanghai	NNP	LOCATION	14	nmod	-
16	,	,	,	O	16	punct	-
17	China	China	NNP	LOCATION	16	appos	-
18	in	in	IN	O	20	case	-
19	response	response	NN	O	7	nmod	0
20	to	to	TO	O	23	case	-
21	increasing	increase	VBG	O	23	amod	0
22	criticism	criticism	NN	O	20	nmod	0
23	of	of	IN	O	27	case	-
24	the	the	DT	O	27	det	-
25	opium	opium	NN	O	27	compound	1
26	trade	trade	NN	O	23	nmod	0
27	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	Hanna	Hanna	NNP	PERSON	2	nsubj	-
1	meandered	meander	VBD	O	0	ROOT	1
2	around	around	IN	O	6	case	-
3	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
4	southeastern	southeastern	JJ	O	6	amod	0
5	Bahamas	Bahamas	NNPS	LOCATION	2	nmod	-
6	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
7	weakening	weaken	VBG	O	2	advcl	0
8	to	to	TO	O	12	case	-
9	a	a	DT	O	12	det	-
10	tropical	tropical	JJ	O	12	amod	0
11	storm	storm	NN	O	8	nmod	0
12	while	while	IN	O	15	mark	-
13	also	also	RB	O	15	advmod	0
14	dumping	dump	VBG	O	8	advcl	0
15	heavy	heavy	JJ	O	17	amod	0
16	rain	rain	NN	O	15	dobj	0
17	on	on	IN	O	20	case	-
18	already-devastated	already-devastated	JJ	O	20	amod	0
19	Haiti	Haiti	NNP	LOCATION	15	nmod	-
20	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	During	during	IN	O	3	case	-
1	sexual	sexual	JJ	O	3	amod	0
2	intercourse	intercourse	NN	O	10	nmod	0
3	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
4	seminal	seminal	JJ	O	6	amod	0
5	fluid	fluid	NN	O	10	nsubj	0
6	containing	contain	VBG	O	6	acl	0
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	-
8	sperm	sperm	NN	O	7	dobj	0
9	comes	come	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
10	out	out	RP	O	10	compound:prt	-
11	through	through	IN	O	15	case	-
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
13	urethral	urethral	JJ	O	15	amod	0
14	opening	opening	NN	O	10	nmod	0
15	when	when	WRB	O	19	advmod	-
16	a	a	DT	O	19	det	-
17	male	male	JJ	O	19	amod	0
18	ejaculates	ejaculate	NNS	O	15	dep	0
19	.	.	.	O	10	punct	-

0	By	by	IN	O	2	case	-
1	1960	1960	CD	DATE	5	nmod	-
2	he	he	PRP	O	5	nsubj	-
3	had	have	VBD	O	5	aux	0
4	developed	develop	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	the	the	DT	O	8	det	-
6	short	short	JJ	O	8	amod	0
7	story	story	NN	O	5	dobj	0
8	into	into	IN	O	11	case	-
9	a	a	DT	O	11	det	-
10	screenplay	screenplay	NN	O	5	nmod	0
11	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
12	and	and	CC	O	5	cc	-
13	envisaged	envisage	VBD	O	5	conj	0
14	it	it	PRP	O	14	dobj	-
15	as	as	IN	O	17	mark	-
16	containing	contain	VBG	O	15	acl	0
17	a	a	DT	O	20	det	-
18	suitable	suitable	JJ	O	20	amod	0
19	role	role	NN	O	17	dobj	0
20	for	for	IN	O	22	case	-
21	Monroe	Monroe	NNP	PERSON	20	nmod	-
22	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Published	publish	VBN	O	8	advcl	0
1	by	by	IN	O	4	case	-
2	Tor	Tor	NNP	MISC	4	compound	-
3	Books	Books	NNPS	MISC	1	nmod	-
4	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
5	it	it	PRP	O	8	nsubjpass	-
6	was	be	VBD	O	8	auxpass	0
7	released	release	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
8	on	on	IN	O	10	case	-
9	August	August	NNP	DATE	8	nmod	-
10	15	15	CD	DATE	10	nummod	-
11	,	,	,	DATE	10	punct	-
12	1994	1994	CD	DATE	10	nummod	-
13	in	in	IN	O	15	case	-
14	hardcover	hardcover	NN	O	10	nmod	0
15	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
16	and	and	CC	O	8	cc	-
17	in	in	IN	O	19	case	-
18	paperback	paperback	NN	O	8	conj	0
19	on	on	IN	O	21	case	-
20	July	July	NNP	DATE	19	nmod	-
21	15	15	CD	DATE	21	nummod	-
22	,	,	,	DATE	21	punct	-
23	1997	1997	CD	DATE	21	nummod	-
24	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	last	last	JJ	O	3	amod	0
2	event	event	NN	O	5	nsubjpass	0
3	was	be	VBD	O	5	auxpass	0
4	held	hold	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	on	on	IN	O	7	case	-
6	June	June	NNP	DATE	5	nmod	-
7	11	11	CD	DATE	7	nummod	-
8	,	,	,	DATE	7	punct	-
9	2000	2000	CD	DATE	7	nummod	-
10	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
11	not	not	RB	O	15	neg	0
12	to	to	TO	O	15	mark	-
13	be	be	VB	O	15	auxpass	0
14	held	hold	VBN	O	7	acl	0
15	again	again	RB	O	15	advmod	0
16	due	due	JJ	O	20	case	0
17	to	to	TO	O	17	mwe	-
18	the	the	DT	O	20	det	-
19	acquisition	acquisition	NN	O	15	nmod	0
20	of	of	IN	O	22	case	-
21	WCW	WCW	NNP	ORGANIZATION	20	nmod	-
22	by	by	IN	O	26	case	-
23	World	World	NNP	ORGANIZATION	26	compound	-
24	Wrestling	Wrestling	NNP	ORGANIZATION	26	compound	-
25	Federation	Federation	NNP	ORGANIZATION	20	nmod	-
26	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	A	a	DT	O	2	det	-
1	frenulum	frenulum	NN	O	6	nsubj	1
2	is	be	VBZ	O	6	cop	0
3	a	a	DT	O	6	det	-
4	small	small	JJ	O	6	amod	0
5	fold	fold	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
6	of	of	IN	O	8	case	-
7	tissue	tissue	NN	O	6	nmod	0
8	that	that	WDT	O	10	nsubj	-
9	secures	secure	VBZ	O	8	acl:relcl	0
10	or	or	CC	O	10	cc	-
11	restricts	restrict	VBZ	O	10	conj	0
12	the	the	DT	O	14	det	-
13	motion	motion	NN	O	10	dobj	0
14	of	of	IN	O	18	case	-
15	a	a	DT	O	18	det	-
16	mobile	mobile	JJ	O	18	amod	0
17	organ	organ	NN	O	14	nmod	0
18	in	in	IN	O	21	case	-
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	body	body	NN	O	18	nmod	0
21	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	Das	Das	NNP	PERSON	2	compound	-
1	Rheingold	Rheingold	NNP	PERSON	5	nsubj	-
2	is	be	VBZ	O	5	cop	0
3	the	the	DT	O	5	det	-
4	first	first	JJ	ORDINAL	0	ROOT	0
5	of	of	IN	O	9	case	-
6	the	the	DT	O	9	det	-
7	four	four	CD	NUMBER	9	nummod	-
8	operas	opera	NNS	O	5	nmod	0
9	that	that	WDT	O	11	nsubj	-
10	comprise	comprise	VBP	O	9	acl:relcl	0
11	Der	Der	NNP	O	15	compound	-
12	Ring	Ring	NNP	O	15	compound	-
13	des	des	NNP	O	15	compound	0
14	Nibelungen	Nibelungen	NNP	PERSON	11	dobj	-
15	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
16	by	by	IN	O	19	case	-
17	Richard	Richard	NNP	PERSON	19	compound	-
18	Wagner	Wagner	NNP	PERSON	5	nmod	-
19	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	purpose	purpose	NN	O	7	nsubj	0
2	of	of	IN	O	5	case	-
3	public	public	JJ	O	5	amod	0
4	speaking	speaking	NN	O	2	nmod	0
5	can	can	MD	O	7	aux	-
6	range	range	VB	O	0	ROOT	0
7	from	from	IN	O	10	mark	-
8	simply	simply	RB	O	10	advmod	0
9	transmitting	transmit	VBG	O	7	advcl	0
10	information	information	NN	O	10	dobj	0
11	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
12	to	to	TO	O	14	mark	-
13	motivating	motivate	VBG	O	7	advcl	0
14	people	people	NNS	O	14	dobj	0
15	to	to	TO	O	17	mark	-
16	act	act	VB	O	14	xcomp	0
17	,	,	,	O	17	punct	-
18	to	to	TO	O	21	mark	-
19	simply	simply	RB	O	21	advmod	0
20	telling	tell	VBG	O	17	advcl	0
21	a	a	DT	O	23	det	-
22	story	story	NN	O	21	dobj	0
23	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	Helen	Helen	NNP	PERSON	2	compound	-
1	Hunt	Hunt	NNP	PERSON	5	nsubjpass	-
2	has	have	VBZ	O	5	aux	0
3	been	be	VBN	O	5	auxpass	0
4	recognized	recognize	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	extensively	extensively	RB	O	5	advmod	0
6	in	in	IN	O	9	case	-
7	her	she	PRP$	O	9	nmod:poss	-
8	career	career	NN	O	5	nmod	0
9	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-
10	In	in	IN	O	12	case	-
11	1998	1998	CD	DATE	14	nmod	-
12	she	she	PRP	O	14	nsubj	-
13	become	become	VB	O	5	parataxis	0
14	the	the	DT	O	17	det	-
15	second	second	JJ	ORDINAL	17	amod	0
16	actress	actress	NN	O	14	xcomp	0
17	to	to	TO	O	19	mark	-
18	win	win	VB	O	14	xcomp	0
19	a	a	DT	O	23	det	-
20	Golden	Golden	NNP	MISC	23	compound	-
21	Globe	Globe	NNP	MISC	23	compound	-
22	Award	award	NN	MISC	19	dobj	-
23	,	,	,	O	23	punct	-
24	an	a	DT	O	27	det	-
25	Academy	academy	NN	MISC	27	compound	-
26	Award	award	NN	MISC	23	conj	-
27	and	and	CC	O	23	cc	-
28	an	a	DT	O	31	det	-
29	Emmy	Emmy	NNP	O	31	compound	-
30	Award	award	NN	O	23	conj	-
31	in	in	IN	O	35	case	-
32	the	the	DT	DATE	35	det	-
33	same	same	JJ	DATE	35	amod	0
34	year	year	NN	DATE	31	nmod	-
35	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Dry	Dry	NNP	O	2	compound	0
1	air	air	NN	O	3	nsubj	0
2	wrapping	wrap	VBG	O	11	csubj	0
3	around	around	IN	O	7	case	-
4	the	the	DT	O	7	det	-
5	southern	southern	JJ	O	7	amod	0
6	periphery	periphery	NN	O	3	nmod	0
7	of	of	IN	O	10	case	-
8	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
9	cyclone	cyclone	NN	O	7	nmod	0
10	eroded	erode	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
11	most	most	JJS	O	11	dobj	0
12	of	of	IN	O	16	case	-
13	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
14	deep	deep	JJ	O	16	amod	0
15	convection	convection	NN	O	12	nmod	0
16	by	by	IN	O	18	case	-
17	early	early	JJ	O	11	nmod	0
18	on	on	IN	O	20	case	-
19	September	September	NNP	DATE	18	nmod	-
20	12	12	CD	DATE	20	nummod	-
21	.	.	.	O	11	punct	-

0	George	George	NNP	PERSON	2	compound	-
1	Harrison	Harrison	NNP	PERSON	3	nsubj	-
2	described	describe	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
3	it	it	PRP	O	3	dobj	-
4	in	in	IN	O	6	case	-
5	1969	1969	CD	DATE	3	nmod	-
6	as	as	IN	O	9	case	-
7	``	``	``	O	9	punct	-
8	one	one	CD	NUMBER	3	nmod	0
9	of	of	IN	O	14	case	-
10	those	those	DT	O	14	det	-
11	instant	instant	JJ	O	14	amod	1
12	whistle-along	whistle-along	JJ	O	14	amod	1
13	tunes	tune	NNS	O	9	nmod	0
14	which	which	WDT	O	18	dobj	-
15	some	some	DT	O	17	det	-
16	people	people	NNS	O	18	nsubj	0
17	hate	hate	VBP	O	14	acl:relcl	0
18	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
19	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
20	other	other	JJ	O	22	amod	0
21	people	people	NNS	O	9	conj	0
22	really	really	RB	O	24	advmod	0
23	like	like	IN	O	22	dep	-
24	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	Pennines	pennine	NNS	O	3	nsubj	-
2	constitute	constitute	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
3	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
4	main	main	JJ	O	6	amod	0
5	watershed	watershed	NN	O	3	dobj	0
6	in	in	IN	O	9	case	-
7	northern	northern	JJ	O	9	amod	0
8	England	England	NNP	LOCATION	6	nmod	-
9	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
10	dividing	divide	VBG	O	3	advcl	0
11	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
12	eastern	eastern	JJ	O	16	amod	0
13	and	and	CC	O	13	cc	-
14	western	western	JJ	O	13	conj	0
15	parts	part	NNS	O	11	dobj	0
16	of	of	IN	O	19	case	-
17	the	the	DT	O	19	det	-
18	country	country	NN	O	16	nmod	0
19	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	Junior	Junior	NNP	O	3	compound	-
2	Certificate	Certificate	NNP	O	5	nsubjpass	-
3	is	be	VBZ	O	5	auxpass	0
4	earned	earn	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	by	by	IN	O	7	mark	-
6	passing	pass	VBG	O	5	advcl	0
7	a	a	DT	O	10	det	-
8	compulsory	compulsory	JJ	O	10	amod	0
9	exam	exam	NN	O	7	dobj	0
10	that	that	WDT	O	12	nsubj	-
11	takes	take	VBZ	O	10	acl:relcl	0
12	place	place	NN	O	12	dobj	0
13	in	in	IN	O	16	case	-
14	secondary	secondary	JJ	O	16	amod	0
15	schools	school	NNS	O	12	nmod	0
16	in	in	IN	O	19	case	-
17	the	the	DT	O	19	det	-
18	Republic	republic	NN	LOCATION	12	nmod	-
19	of	of	IN	LOCATION	21	case	-
20	Ireland	Ireland	NNP	LOCATION	19	nmod	-
21	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	At	at	IN	O	3	case	-
1	the	the	DT	DATE	3	det	-
2	end	end	NN	DATE	10	nmod	0
3	of	of	IN	DATE	7	case	-
4	the	the	DT	DATE	7	det	-
5	20th	20th	JJ	DATE	7	amod	0
6	century	century	NN	DATE	3	nmod	0
7	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
8	scientists	scientist	NNS	O	10	nsubj	0
9	did	do	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
10	much	much	JJ	O	12	amod	0
11	research	research	NN	O	10	dobj	0
12	about	about	IN	O	14	case	-
13	dyslexia	dyslexia	NN	O	12	nmod	0
14	and	and	CC	O	10	cc	-
15	discovered	discover	VBD	O	10	conj	0
16	some	some	DT	O	16	dobj	-
17	of	of	IN	O	20	case	-
18	the	the	DT	O	20	det	-
19	reasons	reason	NNS	O	17	nmod	0
20	that	that	IN	O	24	mark	-
21	people	people	NNS	O	24	nsubj	0
22	are	be	VBP	O	24	cop	0
23	dyslexic	dyslexic	JJ	O	20	ccomp	0
24	.	.	.	O	10	punct	-

0	A	a	DT	O	3	det	-
1	composite	composite	JJ	O	3	amod	0
2	number	number	NN	O	12	nsubj	0
3	(	(	CD	NUMBER	3	nummod	-
4	or	or	CC	O	3	cc	-
5	simply	simply	RB	O	7	advmod	0
6	composite	composite	JJ	O	8	amod	-
7	)	)	NN	O	3	conj	0
8	is	be	VBZ	O	12	cop	0
9	a	a	DT	O	12	det	-
10	natural	natural	JJ	O	12	amod	-
11	number	number	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
12	,	,	,	O	12	punct	-
13	that	that	WDT	O	17	nsubjpass	0
14	can	can	MD	O	17	aux	0
15	be	be	VB	O	17	auxpass	-
16	obtained	obtain	VBN	O	12	acl:relcl	-
17	by	by	IN	O	22	case	0
18	multiplying	multiply	VBG	O	22	amod	-
19	prime	prime	JJ	O	22	amod	0
20	number	number	NN	O	22	compound	-
21	s.	s.	NN	O	17	nmod	-
22	For	for	IN	O	24	case	0
23	example	example	NN	O	17	nmod	-
24	,	,	,	O	12	punct	1
25	the	the	DT	O	27	det	-
26	number	number	NN	O	32	nsubjpass	0
27	9	9	CD	NUMBER	27	nummod	-
28	''	''	''	O	27	punct	0
29	can	can	MD	O	32	aux	0
30	be	be	VB	O	32	auxpass	0
31	gotten	get	VBN	O	12	dep	0
32	by	by	IN	O	34	mark	-
33	multiplying	multiply	VBG	O	32	advcl	-
34	''	''	''	O	34	punct	-
35	3	3	CD	NUMBER	34	dobj	-
36	with	with	IN	O	38	case	-
37	3	3	CD	NUMBER	36	nmod	-
38	''	''	''	O	32	punct	-
39	.	.	.	O	12	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	conspirators	conspirator	NNS	O	3	nsubj	1
2	learned	learn	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
3	of	of	IN	O	6	case	0
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	0
5	letter	letter	NN	O	3	nmod	-
6	the	the	DT	DATE	9	det	-
7	following	follow	VBG	DATE	9	amod	0
8	day	day	NN	DATE	6	nmod:tmod	-
9	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
10	but	but	CC	O	3	cc	0
11	resolved	resolve	VBD	O	3	conj	0
12	to	to	TO	O	14	mark	-
13	go	go	VB	O	12	xcomp	0
14	ahead	ahead	RB	O	14	advmod	-
15	with	with	IN	O	18	case	-
16	their	they	PRP$	O	18	nmod:poss	-
17	plan	plan	NN	O	14	nmod	0
18	,	,	,	O	12	punct	0
19	especially	especially	RB	O	23	advmod	0
20	after	after	IN	O	23	mark	-
21	Fawkes	fawke	NN	PERSON	23	nsubj	0
22	inspected	inspect	VBD	O	12	advcl	-
23	the	the	DT	O	25	det	-
24	undercroft	undercroft	NN	O	23	dobj	-
25	and	and	CC	O	23	cc	-
26	found	find	VBD	O	23	conj	-
27	that	that	IN	O	32	mark	-
28	nothing	nothing	NN	O	32	nsubjpass	-
29	had	have	VBD	O	32	aux	-
30	been	be	VBN	O	32	auxpass	-
31	touched	touch	VBN	O	27	ccomp	-
32	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	These	these	DT	O	2	det	-
1	effigies	effigy	NNS	O	5	nsubjpass	-
2	would	would	MD	O	5	aux	-
3	be	be	VB	O	5	auxpass	-
4	exhibited	exhibit	VBN	O	0	ROOT	-
5	in	in	IN	O	8	case	1
6	the	the	DT	O	8	det	0
7	street	street	NN	O	5	nmod	-
8	,	,	,	O	5	punct	1
9	to	to	TO	O	11	mark	-
10	collect	collect	VB	O	5	xcomp	-
11	money	money	NN	O	11	dobj	-
12	for	for	IN	O	14	case	-
13	fireworks	firework	NNS	O	12	nmod	-
14	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
15	although	although	IN	O	20	mark	-
16	this	this	DT	O	18	det	0
17	practice	practice	NN	O	20	nsubj	-
18	is	be	VBZ	O	20	aux	1
19	becoming	become	VBG	O	5	advcl	-
20	less	less	RBR	O	22	advmod	0
21	common	common	JJ	O	20	xcomp	-
22	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	By	by	IN	O	2	case	-
1	March	March	NNP	DATE	7	nmod	-
2	1605	1605	CD	DATE	2	nummod	1
3	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
4	they	they	PRP	O	7	nsubj	0
5	had	have	VBD	O	7	aux	0
6	filled	fill	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	-
8	undercroft	undercroft	NN	O	7	dobj	0
9	underneath	underneath	IN	O	12	case	-
10	the	the	DT	O	12	det	1
11	House	House	NNP	ORGANIZATION	7	nmod	-
12	of	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	14	case	0
13	Lords	Lords	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	12	nmod	0
14	with	with	IN	O	17	case	0
15	36	36	CD	NUMBER	17	nummod	-
16	barrels	barrel	NNS	O	12	nmod	0
17	of	of	IN	O	19	case	-
18	gunpowder	gunpowder	NN	O	17	nmod	-
19	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
20	concealed	conceal	VBN	O	7	xcomp	0
21	under	under	IN	O	24	case	0
22	a	a	DT	O	24	det	-
23	store	store	NN	O	21	nmod	-
24	of	of	IN	O	27	case	-
25	winter	winter	NN	DATE	27	compound	-
26	fuel	fuel	NN	O	24	nmod	-
27	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	Rhynie	Rhynie	NNP	MISC	3	compound	-
2	chert	chert	NN	O	4	nsubj	0
3	contains	contain	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
4	exceptionally	exceptionally	RB	O	6	advmod	0
5	preserved	preserved	JJ	O	7	amod	0
6	plant	plant	NN	O	4	dobj	-
7	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
8	fungus	fungus	NN	O	7	conj	0
9	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
10	lichen	lichen	NN	O	7	conj	0
11	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	-
12	animal	animal	NN	O	14	compound	0
13	material	material	NN	O	7	conj	-
14	preserved	preserve	VBN	O	7	acl	-
15	in	in	IN	O	17	case	0
16	place	place	NN	O	15	nmod	0
17	by	by	IN	O	22	case	0
18	an	a	DT	O	22	det	-
19	overlying	overlying	JJ	O	22	amod	-
20	volcanic	volcanic	JJ	O	22	amod	0
21	deposit	deposit	NN	O	15	nmod	0
22	.	.	.	O	4	punct	1

0	When	when	WRB	O	6	advmod	-
1	an	a	DT	O	3	det	0
2	insect	insect	NN	O	6	nsubj	-
3	or	or	CC	O	3	cc	0
4	spider	spider	NN	O	3	conj	0
5	crawls	crawl	VBZ	O	17	advcl	-
6	along	along	IN	O	9	case	0
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	0
8	leaves	leaf	NNS	O	6	nmod	-
9	and	and	CC	O	6	cc	0
10	touches	touch	NNS	O	6	conj	-
11	a	a	DT	O	13	det	-
12	hair	hair	NN	O	11	dobj	-
13	,	,	,	O	17	punct	0
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	0
15	trap	trap	NN	O	17	nsubj	0
16	closes	close	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
17	only	only	RB	O	17	advmod	-
18	if	if	IN	O	24	mark	-
19	a	a	DT	O	22	det	0
20	different	different	JJ	O	22	amod	-
21	hair	hair	NN	O	24	nsubjpass	-
22	is	be	VBZ	O	24	auxpass	0
23	contacted	contact	VBN	O	17	advcl	0
24	within	within	IN	O	27	case	-
25	twenty	twenty	CD	DURATION	27	nummod	0
26	seconds	seconds	NNS	DURATION	24	nmod	-
27	of	of	IN	O	31	case	-
28	the	the	DT	O	31	det	-
29	first	first	JJ	ORDINAL	31	amod	0
30	touch	touch	NN	O	27	nmod	-
31	.	.	.	O	17	punct	-

0	There	there	EX	O	2	expl	-
1	are	be	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
2	many	many	JJ	O	5	amod	0
3	different	different	JJ	O	5	amod	-
4	tribal	tribal	JJ	O	8	amod	-
5	and	and	CC	O	5	cc	-
6	ethnic	ethnic	JJ	O	5	conj	-
7	groups	group	NNS	O	2	nsubj	0
8	of	of	IN	O	10	case	-
9	people	people	NNS	O	8	nmod	0
10	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
11	though	though	IN	O	17	mark	-
12	the	the	DT	O	14	det	0
13	country	country	NN	O	17	nsubjpass	-
14	is	be	VBZ	O	17	auxpass	0
15	chiefly	chiefly	RB	O	17	advmod	-
16	divided	divide	VBN	O	2	advcl	-
17	between	between	IN	O	20	case	-
18	the	the	DT	O	20	det	-
19	north	north	NN	O	17	nmod	0
20	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
21	which	which	WDT	O	23	nsubj	-
22	has	have	VBZ	O	20	acl:relcl	0
23	more	more	JJR	O	26	amod	-
24	Arabic	arabic	JJ	MISC	26	amod	0
25	people	people	NNS	O	23	dobj	0
26	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
27	and	and	CC	O	20	cc	-
28	the	the	DT	O	30	det	-
29	south	south	NN	O	20	conj	-
30	,	,	,	O	30	punct	-
31	which	which	WDT	O	33	nsubj	-
32	has	have	VBZ	O	30	acl:relcl	-
33	more	more	JJR	O	35	amod	-
34	people	people	NNS	O	33	dobj	-
35	of	of	IN	O	38	case	-
36	African	african	JJ	MISC	38	amod	-
37	descent	descent	NN	O	35	nmod	-
38	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	A	a	DT	O	2	det	-
1	woman	woman	NN	O	8	nsubj	-
2	may	may	MD	O	8	aux	-
3	,	,	,	O	8	punct	0
4	for	for	IN	O	6	case	0
5	instance	instance	NN	O	8	nmod	0
6	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
7	allow	allow	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
8	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
9	top	top	NN	O	8	dobj	-
10	of	of	IN	O	13	case	-
11	her	she	PRP$	O	13	nmod:poss	0
12	brassiere	brassiere	NN	O	10	nmod	0
13	to	to	TO	O	15	mark	-
14	peek	peek	NN	O	8	xcomp	-
15	out	out	RP	O	15	compound:prt	0
16	from	from	IN	O	20	case	-
17	under	under	IN	O	20	case	-
18	her	she	PRP$	O	20	nmod:poss	0
19	collar	collar	NN	O	15	nmod	-
20	,	,	,	O	15	punct	0
21	or	or	CC	O	15	cc	0
22	wear	wear	VB	O	15	conj	-
23	a	a	DT	O	26	det	-
24	see-through	see-through	JJ	O	26	amod	-
25	blouse	blouse	NN	O	23	dobj	-
26	over	over	IN	O	28	case	-
27	it	it	PRP	O	23	nmod	-
28	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	3	case	0
1	1977	1977	CD	DATE	3	nummod	0
2	Harrison	Harrison	NNP	PERSON	6	nsubj	0
3	was	be	VBD	O	6	cop	-
4	more	more	RBR	O	6	advmod	0
5	candid	candid	JJ	O	0	ROOT	-
6	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
7	describing	describe	VBG	O	6	xcomp	-
8	it	it	PRP	O	8	dobj	0
9	as	as	IN	O	13	case	0
10	``	``	``	O	13	punct	-
11	so	so	RB	O	13	advmod	0
12	fruity	fruity	JJ	O	8	nmod	-
13	''	''	''	O	13	punct	0
14	but	but	CC	O	13	cc	-
15	added	add	VBD	O	13	conj	0
16	``	``	``	O	19	punct	-
17	we	we	PRP	O	19	nsubj	0
18	did	do	VBD	O	16	ccomp	-
19	a	a	DT	O	22	det	0
20	good	good	JJ	O	22	amod	-
21	job	job	NN	O	19	dobj	0
22	on	on	IN	O	24	case	-
23	it	it	PRP	O	19	nmod	0
24	''	''	''	O	19	punct	-
25	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	Human	human	JJ	O	2	amod	-
1	fertility	fertility	NN	O	3	nsubj	-
2	depends	depend	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
3	on	on	IN	O	5	case	0
4	factors	factor	NNS	O	3	nmod	-
5	of	of	IN	O	7	case	-
6	nutrition	nutrition	NN	O	5	nmod	0
7	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
8	sexual	sexual	JJ	O	10	amod	0
9	behavior	behavior	NN	O	8	root	0
10	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
11	culture	culture	NN	O	10	conj	-
12	,	,	,	O	10	punct	0
13	instinct	instinct	NN	O	10	conj	0
14	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
15	endocrinology	endocrinology	NN	O	10	conj	0
16	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
17	timing	timing	NN	O	10	conj	-
18	,	,	,	O	10	punct	0
19	economics	economics	NNS	O	10	conj	0
20	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
21	way	way	NN	O	10	conj	0
22	of	of	IN	O	24	case	0
23	life	life	NN	O	22	nmod	-
24	,	,	,	O	10	punct	0
25	and	and	CC	O	10	cc	0
26	emotions	emotion	NNS	O	10	conj	0
27	.	.	.	O	10	punct	0

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	ISTD	istd	NN	O	3	nsubj	-
2	provides	provide	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
3	training	training	NN	O	3	dobj	0
4	in	in	IN	O	7	case	0
5	a	a	DT	O	7	det	-
6	range	range	NN	O	4	nmod	0
7	of	of	IN	O	10	case	0
8	dance	dance	NN	O	10	compound	-
9	styles	style	NNS	O	7	nmod	-
10	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
11	with	with	IN	O	14	case	-
12	examination	examination	NN	O	14	compound	-
13	syllabi	syllabus	NNS	O	3	nmod	-
14	for	for	IN	O	16	case	-
15	students	student	NNS	O	14	nmod	-
16	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
17	and	and	CC	O	3	cc	0
18	training	training	NN	O	20	compound	0
19	courses	course	NNS	O	3	conj	-
20	for	for	IN	O	22	case	-
21	people	people	NNS	O	20	nmod	-
22	wishing	wish	VBG	O	22	acl	-
23	to	to	TO	O	25	mark	-
24	become	become	VB	O	23	xcomp	-
25	certified	certified	JJ	O	28	amod	-
26	dance	dance	NN	O	28	compound	-
27	teachers	teacher	NNS	O	25	xcomp	-
28	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	Since	since	IN	O	8	mark	-
1	1972	1972	CD	DATE	8	dep	1
2	he	he	PRP	O	8	nsubj	-
3	has	have	VBZ	O	8	aux	0
4	been	be	VBN	O	8	cop	0
5	a	a	DT	O	8	det	0
6	full	full	JJ	O	8	amod	0
7	professor	professor	NN	O	0	ROOT	-
8	at	at	IN	O	12	case	0
9	the	the	DT	O	12	det	0
10	Technical	Technical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	12	compound	-
11	University	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	8	nmod	-
12	of	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	14	case	0
13	Berlin	Berlin	NNP	LOCATION	12	nmod	1
14	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
15	where	where	WRB	O	19	advmod	-
16	he	he	PRP	O	19	nsubj	0
17	is	be	VBZ	O	19	aux	0
18	heading	head	VBG	O	8	advcl	0
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	Department	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	19	dobj	1
21	of	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	23	case	-
22	Bionics	Bionics	NNP	ORGANIZATION	21	nmod	-
23	and	and	CC	O	23	cc	-
24	Evolution	Evolution	NNP	O	26	compound	-
25	Techniques	Techniques	NNPS	O	23	conj	-
26	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	These	these	DT	O	7	nsubj	-
1	were	be	VBD	O	7	cop	0
2	the	the	DT	O	7	det	0
3	first	first	JJ	ORDINAL	7	amod	-
4	serious	serious	JJ	O	7	amod	-
5	technical	technical	JJ	O	7	amod	0
6	applications	application	NNS	O	0	ROOT	-
7	of	of	IN	O	10	case	-
8	artificial	artificial	JJ	O	10	amod	-
9	evolution	evolution	NN	O	7	nmod	-
10	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
11	an	a	DT	O	14	det	-
12	important	important	JJ	O	14	amod	-
13	subset	subset	NN	O	10	appos	-
14	of	of	IN	O	19	case	0
15	the	the	DT	O	19	det	0
16	still	still	RB	O	18	advmod	0
17	growing	grow	VBG	O	19	amod	-
18	field	field	NN	O	14	nmod	0
19	of	of	IN	O	21	case	-
20	bionics	bionic	NNS	O	19	nmod	0
21	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	As	as	IN	O	3	case	-
1	far	far	RB	O	3	advmod	0
2	away	away	RB	O	17	nmod	-
3	as	as	IN	O	6	case	1
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	island	island	NN	O	3	nmod	1
6	of	of	IN	O	8	case	-
7	Malta	Malta	NNP	LOCATION	6	nmod	0
8	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
9	in	in	IN	O	13	case	0
10	the	the	DT	O	13	det	-
11	Mediterranean	Mediterranean	NNP	LOCATION	13	compound	0
12	Sea	Sea	NNP	LOCATION	3	nmod	0
13	,	,	,	O	17	punct	-
14	revelers	reveler	NNS	O	17	nsubjpass	0
15	are	be	VBP	O	17	auxpass	-
16	encouraged	encourage	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
17	to	to	TO	O	19	mark	-
18	drink	drink	VB	O	17	xcomp	0
19	Mexican	mexican	JJ	MISC	21	amod	0
20	beer	beer	NN	O	19	dobj	-
21	on	on	IN	O	23	case	0
22	May	May	NNP	DATE	19	nmod	-
23	5	5	CD	DATE	23	nummod	0
24	.	.	.	O	17	punct	0

0	Escapologists	escapologist	NNS	O	2	nsubj	0
1	escape	escape	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
2	from	from	IN	O	4	case	0
3	handcuffs	handcuffs	NNS	O	2	nmod	-
4	,	,	,	O	4	punct	0
5	straitjackets	straitjacket	NNS	O	4	conj	0
6	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
7	cages	cage	NNS	O	4	conj	-
8	,	,	,	O	4	punct	0
9	coffins	coffin	NNS	O	4	conj	-
10	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
11	steel	steel	NN	O	13	compound	-
12	boxes	box	NNS	O	4	conj	-
13	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
14	barrels	barrel	NNS	O	4	conj	-
15	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
16	bags	bag	NNS	O	4	conj	-
17	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
18	burning	burn	VBG	O	20	amod	-
19	buildings	building	NNS	O	4	conj	-
20	,	,	,	O	4	punct	0
21	fish-tanks	fish-tank	NNS	O	4	conj	0
22	and	and	CC	O	4	cc	-
23	other	other	JJ	O	25	amod	0
24	perils	peril	NNS	O	4	conj	-
25	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
26	often	often	RB	O	29	advmod	-
27	in	in	IN	O	29	case	-
28	combination	combination	NN	O	2	nmod	-
29	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	Harry	Harry	NNP	PERSON	3	nsubj	-
1	also	also	RB	O	3	advmod	0
2	becomes	become	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
3	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
4	worthy	worthy	JJ	O	6	amod	0
5	possessor	possessor	NN	O	3	dobj	-
6	of	of	IN	O	11	case	-
7	the	the	DT	O	11	det	-
8	remaining	remain	VBG	O	11	amod	-
9	Deathly	deathly	RB	MISC	11	amod	-
10	Hallows	Hallows	NNPS	MISC	6	nmod	-
11	:	:	:	O	6	punct	-
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
13	Invisibility	invisibility	NN	O	15	compound	0
14	Cloak	cloak	NN	O	6	dep	-
15	and	and	CC	O	15	cc	0
16	the	the	DT	O	19	det	-
17	Resurrection	Resurrection	NNP	O	19	compound	-
18	Stone	Stone	NNP	O	15	conj	-
19	,	,	,	O	15	punct	-
20	hence	hence	RB	O	22	advmod	-
21	becoming	become	VBG	O	15	acl	0
22	the	the	DT	O	25	det	1
23	true	true	JJ	O	25	amod	-
24	Master	master	NN	O	22	xcomp	-
25	of	of	IN	O	27	case	-
26	Death	death	NN	O	25	nmod	-
27	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	storm	storm	NN	O	3	nsubj	0
2	continued	continue	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
3	,	,	,	O	3	punct	0
4	crossing	cross	VBG	O	3	xcomp	-
5	the	the	DT	O	8	det	0
6	Outer	Outer	NNP	LOCATION	8	compound	0
7	Banks	bank	NNS	LOCATION	5	dobj	-
8	of	of	IN	LOCATION	11	case	0
9	North	North	NNP	LOCATION	11	compound	0
10	Carolina	Carolina	NNP	LOCATION	8	nmod	-
11	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
12	and	and	CC	O	3	cc	-
13	retained	retain	VBD	O	3	conj	-
14	its	its	PRP$	O	16	nmod:poss	0
15	strength	strength	NN	O	14	dobj	-
16	until	until	IN	O	18	case	0
17	June	June	NNP	DATE	14	nmod	0
18	20	20	CD	DATE	18	nummod	-
19	when	when	WRB	O	22	advmod	0
20	it	it	PRP	O	22	nsubj	-
21	became	become	VBD	O	14	advcl	-
22	extratropical	extratropical	JJ	O	22	xcomp	-
23	near	near	IN	O	25	case	-
24	Newfoundland	Newfoundland	NNP	LOCATION	23	nmod	-
25	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	Tibooburra	Tibooburra	NNP	LOCATION	2	nsubj	-
1	has	have	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
2	an	a	DT	O	7	det	0
3	arid	arid	JJ	O	7	amod	-
4	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
5	desert	desert	NN	O	7	compound	-
6	climate	climate	NN	O	2	dobj	0
7	with	with	IN	O	9	case	0
8	temperatures	temperature	NNS	O	7	nmod	0
9	soaring	soar	VBG	O	9	acl	-
10	above	above	IN	O	13	case	-
11	40	40	CD	NUMBER	13	nummod	-
12	Celsius	Celsius	NNP	MISC	10	nmod	-
13	in	in	IN	O	15	case	-
14	summer	summer	NN	DATE	10	nmod	0
15	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
16	often	often	RB	O	18	advmod	-
17	reaching	reach	VBG	O	2	advcl	-
18	as	as	RB	O	20	advmod	-
19	high	high	JJ	O	18	xcomp	-
20	as	as	IN	O	23	case	0
21	47	47	CD	NUMBER	23	nummod	0
22	C	c	NN	O	20	nmod	-
23	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	A	a	DT	O	3	det	-
1	Toronto	Toronto	NNP	LOCATION	3	compound	-
2	native	native	NN	O	12	nsubj	0
3	,	,	,	O	3	punct	0
4	Robson	Robson	NNP	PERSON	8	nmod:poss	0
5	's	's	POS	O	5	case	-
6	breakthrough	breakthrough	NN	O	8	compound	0
7	role	role	NN	O	3	appos	-
8	was	be	VBD	O	12	cop	-
9	in	in	IN	O	12	case	0
10	Crazy	Crazy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	12	compound	-
11	Canucks	Canucks	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	0	ROOT	-
12	,	,	,	O	12	punct	0
13	the	the	DT	O	15	det	0
14	story	story	NN	O	12	appos	0
15	of	of	IN	O	22	case	-
16	the	the	DT	O	22	det	0
17	1974	1974	CD	DATE	22	nummod	-
18	World	World	NNP	MISC	22	compound	0
19	Cup	Cup	NNP	MISC	22	compound	-
20	ski	ski	JJ	O	22	amod	-
21	champions	champion	NNS	O	15	nmod	-
22	.	.	.	O	12	punct	-

0	If	if	IN	O	4	mark	-
1	it	it	PRP	O	4	nsubj	-
2	's	be	VBZ	O	4	cop	-
3	good	good	JJ	O	14	advcl	0
4	enough	enough	RB	O	4	advmod	0
5	to	to	TO	O	7	mark	-
6	take	take	VB	O	4	xcomp	0
7	to	to	TO	O	10	case	-
8	your	you	PRP$	O	10	nmod:poss	0
9	psychiatrist	psychiatrist	NN	O	7	nmod	-
10	,	,	,	O	14	punct	0
11	it	it	PRP	O	14	nsubj	-
12	's	be	VBZ	O	14	cop	-
13	good	good	JJ	O	0	ROOT	-
14	enough	enough	RB	O	14	advmod	0
15	to	to	TO	O	17	mark	0
16	make	make	VB	O	15	xcomp	0
17	a	a	DT	O	19	det	-
18	song	song	NN	O	17	dobj	-
19	of	of	IN	O	19	acl	-
20	.	.	.	O	14	punct	-

0	One	one	CD	NUMBER	9	nsubj	0
1	of	of	IN	O	5	case	-
2	the	the	DT	O	5	det	0
3	new	new	JJ	O	5	amod	-
4	tracks	track	NNS	O	1	nmod	-
5	will	will	MD	O	9	aux	0
6	be	be	VB	O	9	cop	0
7	a	a	DT	O	9	det	-
8	duet	duet	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
9	with	with	IN	O	11	case	0
10	one	one	CD	NUMBER	9	nmod	-
11	of	of	IN	O	17	case	-
12	Timbaland	Timbaland	NNP	ORGANIZATION	17	nmod:poss	-
13	's	's	POS	O	13	case	-
14	most	most	RBS	O	16	advmod	-
15	successful	successful	JJ	O	17	amod	-
16	artists	artist	NNS	O	11	nmod	-
17	,	,	,	O	9	punct	0
18	Nelly	Nelly	NNP	PERSON	20	compound	0
19	Furtado	Furtado	NNP	PERSON	9	appos	-
20	.	.	.	O	9	punct	-

0	Earlier	earlier	RBR	O	3	advmod	-
1	that	that	DT	O	3	det	0
2	year	year	NN	DURATION	7	nmod:tmod	-
3	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
4	Ferdinand	Ferdinand	NNP	PERSON	7	nsubj	-
5	had	have	VBD	O	7	aux	1
6	conquered	conquer	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
7	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
8	southern	southern	JJ	O	10	amod	-
9	half	half	NN	O	7	dobj	0
10	of	of	IN	O	13	case	1
11	the	the	DT	O	13	det	-
12	Kingdom	Kingdom	NNP	O	10	nmod	-
13	of	of	IN	O	15	case	-
14	Navarre	Navarre	NNP	LOCATION	13	nmod	0
15	,	,	,	O	13	punct	-
16	which	which	WDT	O	19	nsubjpass	0
17	was	be	VBD	O	19	auxpass	-
18	ruled	rule	VBN	O	13	acl:relcl	-
19	by	by	IN	O	23	case	-
20	a	a	DT	O	23	det	0
21	French	french	JJ	MISC	23	amod	-
22	nobleman	nobleman	NN	O	19	nmod	-
23	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
24	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	-
25	annexed	annex	VBD	O	7	conj	-
26	it	it	PRP	O	26	dobj	-
27	to	to	TO	O	29	case	-
28	Spain	Spain	NNP	LOCATION	26	nmod	-
29	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	Ferdinand	Ferdinand	NNP	PERSON	2	nsubj	-
1	attempted	attempt	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
2	to	to	TO	O	4	mark	0
3	retain	retain	VB	O	2	xcomp	0
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	regency	regency	NN	O	4	dobj	0
6	permanently	permanently	RB	O	4	advmod	-
7	,	,	,	O	2	punct	0
8	but	but	CC	O	2	cc	-
9	was	be	VBD	O	11	auxpass	1
10	rebuffed	rebuff	VBN	O	2	conj	1
11	by	by	IN	O	15	case	-
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	0
13	Castilian	castilian	JJ	MISC	15	amod	1
14	nobility	nobility	NN	O	11	nmod	-
15	and	and	CC	O	11	cc	-
16	replaced	replace	VBN	O	11	conj	0
17	with	with	IN	O	21	case	-
18	Joanna	Joanna	NNP	PERSON	21	nmod:poss	0
19	's	's	POS	O	19	case	-
20	husband	husband	NN	O	17	nmod	-
21	,	,	,	O	21	punct	-
22	who	who	WP	O	24	nsubj	-
23	became	become	VBD	O	21	acl:relcl	-
24	Philip	Philip	NNP	PERSON	26	compound	-
25	I	I	NNP	O	24	xcomp	-
26	of	of	IN	O	28	case	-
27	Castile	Castile	NNP	LOCATION	26	nmod	-
28	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	It	it	PRP	O	6	nsubj	-
1	is	be	VBZ	O	6	cop	-
2	traditionally	traditionally	RB	O	6	advmod	-
3	roughly	roughly	RB	O	5	advmod	-
4	three	three	CD	NUMBER	6	nummod	-
5	metres	metre	NNS	O	0	ROOT	0
6	in	in	IN	O	8	case	-
7	length	length	NN	O	6	nmod	-
8	and	and	CC	O	6	cc	-
9	is	be	VBZ	O	11	auxpass	0
10	made	make	VBN	O	6	conj	0
11	by	by	IN	O	13	mark	0
12	weaving	weave	VBG	O	11	advcl	-
13	yarn	yarn	NN	O	13	dobj	0
14	together	together	RB	O	13	advmod	-
15	with	with	IN	O	19	case	-
16	one	one	CD	NUMBER	19	nmod:poss	-
17	's	's	POS	O	17	case	-
18	fingers	finger	NNS	O	13	nmod	0
19	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	After	after	IN	O	3	case	-
1	Lake	Lake	NNP	PERSON	3	compound	0
2	Trasimene	Trasimene	NNP	PERSON	6	nmod	-
3	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
4	Hannibal	Hannibal	NNP	PERSON	6	nsubj	-
5	stated	state	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
6	,	,	,	O	6	punct	-
7	``	``	``	O	6	punct	-
8	I	I	PRP	O	12	nsubj	-
9	have	have	VBP	O	12	aux	0
10	not	not	RB	O	12	neg	0
11	come	come	VB	O	6	ccomp	-
12	to	to	TO	O	14	mark	-
13	fight	fight	VB	O	12	xcomp	-
14	Italians	Italians	NNPS	MISC	14	dobj	-
15	,	,	,	O	12	punct	-
16	but	but	CC	O	12	cc	-
17	on	on	IN	O	19	case	0
18	behalf	behalf	NN	O	12	conj	0
19	of	of	IN	O	22	case	-
20	the	the	DT	O	22	det	0
21	Italians	Italians	NNPS	MISC	19	nmod	0
22	against	against	IN	O	24	case	-
23	Rome	Rome	NNP	LOCATION	19	nmod	-
24	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	There	there	EX	O	2	expl	-
1	is	be	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
2	another	another	DT	O	4	det	0
3	article	article	NN	O	2	nsubj	0
4	on	on	IN	O	8	case	0
5	the	the	DT	O	8	det	-
6	Belfast	Belfast	NNP	MISC	8	compound	-
7	Agreement	Agreement	NNP	MISC	4	nmod	0
8	,	,	,	O	2	punct	1
9	also	also	RB	O	11	advmod	-
10	called	call	VBD	O	2	dep	0
11	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
12	Good	good	JJ	DATE	15	amod	-
13	Friday	Friday	NNP	DATE	15	compound	0
14	Agreement	Agreement	NNP	O	11	dobj	0
15	,	,	,	O	15	punct	-
16	a	a	DT	O	19	det	-
17	peace	peace	NN	O	19	compound	-
18	accord	accord	NN	O	15	appos	-
19	that	that	WDT	O	22	nsubjpass	0
20	was	be	VBD	O	22	auxpass	0
21	signed	sign	VBN	O	19	acl:relcl	0
22	in	in	IN	O	25	case	-
23	Northern	northern	JJ	LOCATION	25	amod	-
24	Ireland	Ireland	NNP	LOCATION	22	nmod	-
25	in	in	IN	O	27	case	-
26	1998	1998	CD	DATE	22	nmod	-
27	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	-
1	cancer	cancer	NN	O	7	nmod	0
2	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
3	body	body	NN	O	5	compound	-
4	cells	cell	NNS	O	7	nsubj	0
5	are	be	VBP	O	7	aux	-
6	copying	copy	VBG	O	0	ROOT	-
7	their	they	PRP$	O	9	nmod:poss	-
8	contents	contents	NNS	O	7	dobj	0
9	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	-
10	then	then	RB	O	12	advmod	-
11	creating	create	VBG	O	7	conj	-
12	new	new	JJ	O	14	amod	-
13	cells	cell	NNS	O	12	dobj	-
14	with	with	IN	O	17	case	-
15	these	these	DT	O	17	det	0
16	copies	copy	NNS	O	12	nmod	-
17	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
18	but	but	CC	O	7	cc	0
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	body	body	NN	O	22	nsubj	-
21	has	have	VBZ	O	7	conj	-
22	no	no	DT	O	24	neg	0
23	control	control	NN	O	22	dobj	-
24	over	over	IN	O	27	case	1
25	these	these	DT	O	27	det	-
26	reactions	reaction	NNS	O	24	nmod	-
27	.	.	.	O	7	punct	0

0	He	he	PRP	O	3	nsubjpass	-
1	was	be	VBD	O	3	auxpass	0
2	found	find	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
3	at	at	IN	O	9	case	0
4	approximately	approximately	RB	O	6	advmod	0
5	8:30	8:30	CD	TIME	9	nummod	-
6	PM	PM	NNP	TIME	9	compound	-
7	Iraqi	iraqi	JJ	MISC	9	amod	-
8	time	time	NN	O	3	nmod	0
9	on	on	IN	O	11	case	-
10	December	December	NNP	DATE	9	nmod	0
11	13	13	CD	DATE	11	nummod	-
12	,	,	,	O	3	punct	0
13	in	in	IN	O	19	case	-
14	an	a	DT	O	19	det	-
15	underground	underground	JJ	O	19	amod	-
16	''	''	''	O	19	punct	-
17	spider	spider	NN	O	19	compound	1
18	hole	hole	NN	O	3	nmod	-
19	''	''	''	O	19	punct	-
20	at	at	IN	O	23	case	0
21	a	a	DT	O	23	det	-
22	farmhouse	farmhouse	NN	O	19	nmod	0
23	in	in	IN	O	25	case	-
24	ad-Dawr	ad-dawr	NN	O	23	nmod	-
25	near	near	IN	O	30	case	-
26	his	he	PRP$	O	30	nmod:poss	-
27	home	home	NN	O	30	compound	0
28	town	town	NN	O	30	compound	-
29	Tikrit	Tikrit	NNP	LOCATION	25	nmod	-
30	,	,	,	O	3	punct	0
31	in	in	IN	O	35	mark	-
32	what	what	WP	O	35	nsubjpass	-
33	was	be	VBD	O	35	auxpass	-
34	called	call	VBN	O	3	advcl	-
35	Operation	Operation	NNP	O	38	compound	-
36	Red	Red	NNP	O	38	compound	-
37	Dawn	Dawn	NNP	O	35	xcomp	-
38	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	This	this	DT	O	2	det	-
1	consciousness	consciousness	NN	O	5	nsubj	0
2	is	be	VBZ	O	5	cop	-
3	not	not	RB	O	5	neg	1
4	merely	merely	RB	O	0	ROOT	-
5	that	that	IN	O	5	dep	-
6	of	of	IN	O	9	case	-
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	0
8	body	body	NN	O	6	nmod	-
9	or	or	CC	O	9	cc	-
10	mind	mind	NN	O	9	conj	0
11	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	0
12	intellect	intellect	NN	O	9	conj	-
13	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
14	but	but	CC	O	9	cc	-
15	of	of	IN	O	18	case	0
16	a	a	DT	O	18	det	-
17	soul-state	soul-state	NN	O	9	conj	-
18	above	above	IN	O	21	case	-
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	mind	mind	NN	O	18	nmod	-
21	that	that	WDT	O	23	nsubj	-
22	exists	exist	VBZ	O	21	acl:relcl	-
23	within	within	IN	O	23	dep	-
24	and	and	CC	O	24	cc	-
25	beyond	beyond	IN	O	28	case	-
26	our	we	PRP$	O	28	nmod:poss	-
27	existence	existence	NN	O	24	conj	-
28	,	,	,	O	24	punct	-
29	the	the	DT	O	32	det	-
30	pure	pure	JJ	O	32	amod	-
31	Self	self	NN	O	29	root	-
32	of	of	IN	O	34	case	-
33	all	all	DT	O	32	nmod	-
34	.	.	.	O	32	punct	-

0	They	they	PRP	O	2	nsubj	-
1	died	die	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
2	of	of	IN	O	4	case	0
3	tuberculosis	tuberculosis	NN	O	2	nmod	-
4	in	in	IN	O	6	case	-
5	June	June	NNP	DATE	2	nmod	-
6	1825	1825	CD	DATE	6	nummod	0
7	soon	soon	RB	O	12	advmod	-
8	after	after	IN	O	12	mark	-
9	their	they	PRP$	O	11	nmod:poss	-
10	father	father	NN	O	12	nsubj	0
11	removed	remove	VBD	O	2	advcl	-
12	them	they	PRP	O	12	dobj	-
13	from	from	IN	O	16	case	-
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
15	school	school	NN	O	12	nmod	0
16	on	on	IN	O	19	case	-
17	1	1	CD	DATE	19	nummod	-
18	June	June	NNP	DATE	16	nmod	-
19	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	4	det	-
1	Three	three	CD	NUMBER	4	nummod	-
2	Peaks	Peaks	NNP	O	4	compound	0
3	Challenge	Challenge	NNP	O	7	nsubj	-
4	is	be	VBZ	O	7	cop	-
5	a	a	DT	O	7	det	0
6	challenge	challenge	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
7	(	(	VBD	O	7	dep	0
8	a	a	DT	O	11	det	-
9	difficult	difficult	JJ	O	11	amod	-
10	task	task	NN	O	8	dobj	0
11	or	or	CC	O	11	cc	-
12	job	job	NN	O	11	conj	-
13	)	)	CD	NUMBER	13	nummod	0
14	which	which	WDT	O	16	nsubj	0
15	involves	involve	VBZ	O	14	acl:relcl	-
16	climbing	climb	VBG	O	16	xcomp	0
17	three	three	CD	NUMBER	21	nummod	-
18	British	british	JJ	MISC	21	amod	0
19	mountain	mountain	NN	O	21	compound	-
20	s	s	NNS	O	22	nsubj	0
21	(	(	VBP	O	27	csubj	0
22	a	a	DT	O	24	det	-
23	peak	peak	NN	O	22	dobj	-
24	is	be	VBZ	O	27	cop	-
25	the	the	DT	O	27	det	-
26	top	top	NN	O	17	ccomp	-
27	of	of	IN	O	31	case	-
28	a	a	DT	O	31	det	-
29	mountain	mountain	NN	O	31	compound	-
30	)	)	NN	O	27	nmod	-
31	in	in	IN	O	36	case	-
32	less	less	JJR	DURATION	35	advmod	-
33	than	than	IN	DURATION	33	mwe	-
34	24	24	CD	DURATION	36	nummod	-
35	hours	hour	NNS	DURATION	27	nmod	-
36	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	strings	string	NNS	O	3	nsubj	0
2	travel	travel	VBP	O	0	ROOT	-
3	from	from	IN	O	7	case	-
4	near	near	IN	O	7	case	-
5	the	the	DT	O	7	det	-
6	top	top	NN	O	3	nmod	0
7	of	of	IN	O	11	case	-
8	the	the	DT	O	11	det	0
9	``	``	``	O	11	punct	-
10	neck	neck	NN	O	7	nmod	-
11	''	''	''	O	3	punct	-
12	down	down	IN	O	16	case	0
13	the	the	DT	O	16	det	0
14	``	``	``	O	16	punct	0
15	fingerboard	fingerboard	NN	O	3	nmod	-
16	''	''	''	O	16	punct	0
17	and	and	CC	O	3	cc	-
18	on	on	IN	O	24	case	0
19	to	to	TO	O	24	case	-
20	the	the	DT	O	24	det	0
21	``	``	``	O	24	punct	-
22	tail	tail	NN	O	24	compound	0
23	piece	piece	NN	O	3	conj	0
24	''	''	''	O	24	punct	-
25	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	32	32	CD	NUMBER	3	nummod	0
2	teams	team	NNS	O	8	nsubj	-
3	in	in	IN	O	6	case	-
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	finals	final	NNS	O	3	nmod	0
6	then	then	RB	O	8	advmod	0
7	play	play	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
8	for	for	IN	O	11	case	0
9	four	four	CD	DURATION	11	nummod	-
10	weeks	week	NNS	DURATION	8	nmod	0
11	in	in	IN	O	15	case	-
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
13	host	host	NN	O	15	compound	0
14	nation	nation	NN	O	11	nmod	-
15	to	to	TO	O	17	mark	-
16	determine	determine	VB	O	8	xcomp	0
17	the	the	DT	O	22	det	0
18	champion	champion	NN	O	22	compound	-
19	(	(	NN	O	22	compound	0
20	tournament	tournament	NN	O	22	compound	0
21	winner	winner	NN	O	17	dobj	-
22	)	)	NN	O	22	dep	0
23	.	.	.	O	8	punct	0

0	Claudius	Claudius	NNP	PERSON	2	nsubj	-
1	sends	send	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
2	Hamlet	Hamlet	NNP	PERSON	2	dobj	0
3	to	to	TO	O	5	case	0
4	England	England	NNP	LOCATION	2	nmod	0
5	to	to	TO	O	7	mark	0
6	have	have	VB	O	2	xcomp	-
7	him	he	PRP	O	9	nsubj	0
8	killed	kill	VBN	O	7	ccomp	-
9	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
10	but	but	CC	O	2	cc	0
11	his	he	PRP$	O	13	nmod:poss	-
12	embark	embark	VBP	O	15	nsubjpass	-
13	is	be	VBZ	O	15	auxpass	0
14	attacked	attack	VBN	O	2	conj	-
15	by	by	IN	O	17	case	-
16	pirates	pirate	NNS	O	15	nmod	0
17	who	who	WP	O	19	nsubj	0
18	take	take	VBP	O	17	acl:relcl	0
19	Hamlet	Hamlet	NNP	PERSON	21	compound	0
20	prisoner	prisoner	NN	O	19	dobj	0
21	but	but	CC	O	19	cc	-
22	then	then	RB	O	24	advmod	0
23	return	return	VB	O	19	conj	-
24	him	he	PRP	O	24	dobj	0
25	to	to	TO	O	27	case	0
26	Denmark	Denmark	NNP	LOCATION	24	nmod	0
27	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	This	this	DT	O	2	nsubj	-
1	means	mean	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	0
2	that	that	IN	O	32	mark	0
3	if	if	IN	O	7	mark	0
4	a	a	DT	O	6	det	0
5	person	person	NN	O	7	nsubj	-
6	starts	start	VBZ	O	32	advcl	-
7	taking	take	VBG	O	7	xcomp	-
8	heroin	heroin	NN	O	8	dobj	-
9	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
10	crack	crack	NN	O	9	conj	-
11	,	,	,	O	9	punct	-
12	or	or	CC	O	9	cc	-
13	cocaine	cocaine	NN	O	9	conj	-
14	,	,	,	O	32	punct	-
15	that	that	IN	O	21	mark	0
16	persons	person	NNS	O	18	compound	-
17	body	body	NN	O	21	nsubj	-
18	will	will	MD	O	21	aux	0
19	physically	physically	RB	O	21	advmod	-
20	need	need	VB	O	32	advcl	-
21	to	to	TO	O	23	mark	-
22	keep	keep	VB	O	21	xcomp	-
23	taking	take	VBG	O	23	xcomp	-
24	the	the	DT	O	26	det	-
25	drug	drug	NN	O	24	dobj	-
26	,	,	,	O	32	punct	-
27	to	to	TO	O	29	mark	-
28	discontinue	discontinue	VB	O	32	csubj	-
29	use	use	NN	O	29	dobj	-
30	may	may	MD	O	32	aux	-
31	cause	cause	VB	O	2	ccomp	-
32	them	they	PRP	O	32	dobj	-
33	to	to	TO	O	35	mark	-
34	become	become	VB	O	32	xcomp	-
35	sick	sick	JJ	O	35	xcomp	-
36	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	Many	many	JJ	O	2	amod	0
1	artists	artist	NNS	O	4	nsubj	-
2	have	have	VBP	O	4	aux	0
3	had	have	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
4	albums	album	NNS	O	6	nmod:npmod	0
5	altered	altered	JJ	O	4	dobj	-
6	or	or	CC	O	6	cc	-
7	censored	censor	VBN	O	6	conj	0
8	in	in	IN	O	11	case	-
9	some	some	DT	O	11	det	-
10	way	way	NN	O	6	nmod	0
11	by	by	IN	O	14	case	0
12	the	the	DT	O	14	det	-
13	labels	label	NNS	O	6	nmod	-
14	before	before	IN	O	18	mark	-
15	they	they	PRP	O	18	nsubjpass	-
16	are	be	VBP	O	18	auxpass	-
17	released	release	VBN	O	14	acl	-
18	songs	song	NNS	O	18	dobj	-
19	being	be	VBG	O	21	auxpass	-
20	edited	edit	VBN	O	19	acl	-
21	,	,	,	O	21	punct	-
22	artwork	artwork	NN	O	21	conj	-
23	or	or	CC	O	21	cc	-
24	titles	title	NNS	O	27	nsubjpass	-
25	being	be	VBG	O	27	auxpass	-
26	changed	change	VBN	O	21	conj	-
27	,	,	,	O	21	punct	-
28	etc.	etc.	FW	O	21	advmod	-
29	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	He	he	PRP	O	2	nsubj	-
1	held	hold	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
2	several	several	JJ	O	5	amod	-
3	senior	senior	JJ	O	5	amod	-
4	positions	position	NNS	O	2	dobj	0
5	in	in	IN	O	10	case	0
6	the	the	DT	O	10	det	0
7	Royal	Royal	NNP	ORGANIZATION	10	compound	-
8	Flying	Flying	NNP	ORGANIZATION	10	compound	-
9	Corps	Corps	NNP	ORGANIZATION	5	nmod	0
10	during	during	IN	O	14	case	-
11	World	World	NNP	MISC	14	compound	0
12	War	War	NNP	MISC	14	compound	-
13	I	I	NNP	O	2	nmod	-
14	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
15	serving	serve	VBG	O	2	xcomp	-
16	as	as	IN	O	19	case	0
17	the	the	DT	O	19	det	0
18	commander	commander	NN	O	16	nmod	0
19	of	of	IN	O	23	case	0
20	Royal	Royal	NNP	ORGANIZATION	23	compound	-
21	Flying	Flying	NNP	ORGANIZATION	23	compound	0
22	Corps	Corps	NNP	ORGANIZATION	19	nmod	0
23	in	in	IN	O	25	case	0
24	France	France	NNP	LOCATION	19	nmod	0
25	from	from	IN	O	27	case	-
26	1915	1915	CD	DATE	16	nmod	-
27	to	to	TO	DATE	29	case	-
28	1917	1917	CD	DATE	27	nmod	-
29	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	Discovery	Discovery	NNP	O	3	compound	0
1	The	The	NNP	O	3	det	0
2	wreck	wreck	NN	O	5	nsubjpass	0
3	was	be	VBD	O	5	auxpass	0
4	discovered	discover	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	by	by	IN	O	11	case	-
6	a	a	DT	O	11	det	-
7	French	french	JJ	MISC	11	amod	0
8	and	and	CC	O	8	cc	-
9	American	american	JJ	MISC	8	conj	-
10	team	team	NN	O	5	nmod	0
11	led	lead	VBN	O	11	acl	-
12	by	by	IN	O	15	case	0
13	Robert	Robert	NNP	PERSON	15	compound	-
14	Ballard	Ballard	NNP	PERSON	12	nmod	-
15	and	and	CC	O	15	cc	0
16	Jean-Louis	Jean-Louis	NNP	PERSON	18	compound	0
17	Michel	Michel	NNP	PERSON	15	conj	0
18	on	on	IN	O	21	case	-
19	1	1	CD	TIME	21	nummod	-
20	September	September	NNP	DATE	18	nmod	-
21	1985	1985	CD	DATE	21	nummod	0
22	at	at	IN	TIME	24	case	0
23	1:02	1:02	CD	TIME	12	nmod	0
24	in	in	IN	TIME	27	case	-
25	the	the	DT	TIME	27	det	-
26	morning	morning	NN	TIME	24	nmod	-
27	.	.	.	O	5	punct	0

0	They	they	PRP	O	2	nsubj	-
1	die	die	VBP	O	0	ROOT	-
2	because	because	IN	O	7	mark	-
3	their	they	PRP$	O	5	nmod:poss	-
4	neck	neck	NN	O	7	nsubjpass	-
5	is	be	VBZ	O	7	auxpass	-
6	broken	break	VBN	O	2	advcl	0
7	or	or	CC	O	7	cc	0
8	through	through	IN	O	10	mark	-
9	choking	choke	VBG	O	7	conj	-
10	(	(	CD	NUMBER	13	nummod	0
11	asphyxiation	asphyxiation	NN	O	13	compound	-
12	)	)	NN	O	10	dobj	1
13	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
14	if	if	IN	O	20	mark	-
15	the	the	DT	O	17	det	0
16	drop	drop	NN	O	20	nsubj	-
17	is	be	VBZ	O	20	cop	0
18	too	too	RB	O	20	advmod	0
19	small	small	JJ	O	25	advcl	-
20	or	or	CC	O	20	cc	0
21	knot	knot	NN	O	20	conj	-
22	was	be	VBD	O	25	auxpass	-
23	poorly	poorly	RB	O	25	advmod	0
24	made	make	VBN	O	2	parataxis	-
25	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	Classical	classical	JJ	O	2	amod	-
1	physics	physics	NNS	O	4	nsubj	-
2	already	already	RB	O	4	advmod	-
3	had	have	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
4	answers	answer	NNS	O	4	dobj	-
5	for	for	IN	O	8	case	-
6	the	the	DT	O	8	det	0
7	brightness	brightness	NN	O	5	nmod	-
8	of	of	IN	O	11	case	-
9	the	the	DT	O	11	det	0
10	bands	band	NNS	O	8	nmod	0
11	of	of	IN	O	13	case	-
12	color	color	NN	O	11	nmod	-
13	that	that	IN	O	18	mark	-
14	a	a	DT	O	17	det	-
15	hydrogen	hydrogen	NN	O	17	compound	-
16	lamp	lamp	NN	O	18	nsubj	-
17	produces	produce	VBZ	O	5	dep	-
18	,	,	,	O	18	punct	-
19	but	but	CC	O	18	cc	-
20	the	the	DT	O	23	det	0
21	classical	classical	JJ	O	23	amod	0
22	theory	theory	NN	O	24	nsubj	-
23	said	say	VBD	O	18	conj	-
24	that	that	IN	O	31	mark	0
25	there	there	EX	O	31	expl	0
26	should	should	MD	O	31	aux	-
27	be	be	VB	O	31	cop	0
28	a	a	DT	O	31	det	0
29	continuous	continuous	JJ	O	31	amod	-
30	rainbow	rainbow	NN	O	24	ccomp	-
31	,	,	,	O	31	punct	-
32	and	and	CC	O	31	cc	-
33	not	not	RB	O	38	neg	-
34	four	four	CD	NUMBER	38	nummod	-
35	isolated	isolate	VBN	O	38	amod	-
36	color	color	NN	O	38	compound	-
37	bands	band	NNS	O	31	conj	-
38	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	6	det	-
1	United	United	NNP	LOCATION	6	compound	-
2	Kingdom	Kingdom	NNP	LOCATION	6	compound	-
3	Independence	Independence	NNP	ORGANIZATION	6	compound	-
4	Party	Party	NNP	ORGANIZATION	6	compound	0
5	(	(	NN	O	11	nsubj	-
6	often	often	RB	O	8	advmod	1
7	called	call	VBN	O	6	acl	-
8	UKIP	UKIP	NNP	ORGANIZATION	8	xcomp	-
9	,	,	,	O	6	punct	-
10	pronounced	pronounce	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
11	``	``	``	O	11	punct	0
12	yoo-kip	yoo-kip	JJ	O	15	amod	0
13	''	''	''	O	15	punct	-
14	)	)	NN	O	19	nsubj	-
15	is	be	VBZ	O	19	cop	-
16	a	a	DT	O	19	det	-
17	political	political	JJ	O	19	amod	0
18	party	party	NN	O	11	ccomp	-
19	that	that	WDT	O	21	nsubj	-
20	wants	want	VBZ	O	19	acl:relcl	-
21	Britain	Britain	NNP	LOCATION	21	dobj	-
22	to	to	TO	O	24	mark	-
23	leave	leave	VB	O	21	xcomp	-
24	the	the	DT	O	27	det	-
25	European	European	NNP	LOCATION	27	compound	-
26	Union	Union	NNP	LOCATION	24	dobj	-
27	.	.	.	O	11	punct	-

0	Lancelot	Lancelot	NNP	PERSON	3	compound	1
1	de	de	NNP	PERSON	3	compound	-
2	Carles	Carles	NNP	PERSON	4	nsubj	0
3	called	call	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
4	her	she	PRP$	O	4	xcomp	-
5	``	``	``	O	5	punct	0
6	beautiful	beautiful	JJ	O	6	root	-
7	with	with	IN	O	11	case	-
8	an	a	DT	O	11	det	-
9	elegant	elegant	JJ	O	11	amod	-
10	figure	figure	NN	O	7	nmod	0
11	''	''	''	O	11	punct	-
12	,	,	,	O	7	punct	0
13	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	-
14	a	a	DT	O	16	det	-
15	Venetian	Venetian	NNP	MISC	22	nsubj	1
16	in	in	IN	O	18	case	-
17	Paris	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	16	nmod	0
18	in	in	IN	O	20	case	-
19	1528	1528	CD	DATE	16	nmod	0
20	also	also	RB	O	22	advmod	-
21	reported	report	VBD	O	7	conj	0
22	that	that	IN	O	26	mark	0
23	she	she	PRP	O	26	nsubjpass	0
24	was	be	VBD	O	26	auxpass	-
25	said	say	VBN	O	22	ccomp	0
26	to	to	TO	O	29	mark	-
27	be	be	VB	O	29	cop	-
28	beautiful	beautiful	JJ	O	26	xcomp	-
29	.	.	.	O	7	punct	1

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	0
1	2005	2005	CD	DATE	5	nmod	-
2	,	,	,	O	5	punct	0
3	Benson	Benson	NNP	PERSON	5	nsubj	0
4	collaborated	collaborate	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
5	with	with	IN	O	9	case	0
6	artist	artist	NN	O	9	compound	0
7	Jamie	Jamie	NNP	PERSON	9	compound	0
8	McKelvie	McKelvie	NNP	PERSON	5	nmod	-
9	on	on	IN	O	13	case	-
10	a	a	DT	O	13	det	0
11	short	short	JJ	O	13	amod	0
12	story	story	NN	O	5	nmod	-
13	within	within	IN	O	18	case	-
14	the	the	DT	O	18	det	0
15	Image	image	NN	ORGANIZATION	18	compound	0
16	Comics	Comics	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	18	compound	-
17	collection	collection	NN	O	13	nmod	0
18	Four	four	CD	NUMBER	21	nummod	-
19	Letter	letter	NN	O	21	compound	-
20	Worlds	world	NNS	O	18	dep	0
21	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Fired	fire	VBN	O	6	advcl	-
1	by	by	IN	O	3	case	0
2	enthusiasm	enthusiasm	NN	O	1	nmod	0
3	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
4	Tolstoy	Tolstoy	NNP	PERSON	6	nsubj	-
5	returned	return	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
6	to	to	TO	O	9	case	-
7	Yasnaya	Yasnaya	NNP	LOCATION	9	compound	0
8	Polyana	Polyana	NNP	LOCATION	6	nmod	0
9	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
10	founded	found	VBN	O	13	amod	1
11	thirteen	thirteen	CD	NUMBER	13	nummod	0
12	schools	school	NNS	O	9	conj	-
13	for	for	IN	O	18	case	-
14	his	he	PRP$	O	16	nmod:poss	-
15	serfs	serf	NNS	O	18	nmod:poss	0
16	'	'	POS	O	16	case	-
17	children	child	NNS	O	6	nmod	-
18	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
19	based	base	VBN	O	6	xcomp	-
20	on	on	IN	O	25	case	-
21	ground-breaking	ground-breaking	JJ	O	25	amod	-
22	libertarian	libertarian	JJ	O	25	amod	0
23	principles	principle	NNS	O	25	compound	-
24	Tolstoy	Tolstoy	NNP	PERSON	20	nmod	-
25	described	describe	VBD	O	20	dep	0
26	in	in	IN	O	30	case	0
27	his	he	PRP$	O	30	nmod:poss	-
28	1862	1862	CD	DATE	30	nummod	-
29	essay	essay	NN	O	26	nmod	-
30	``	``	``	O	30	punct	-
31	The	The	NNP	O	33	det	-
32	School	School	NNP	O	30	dep	-
33	at	at	IN	O	36	case	-
34	Yasnaya	Yasnaya	NNP	LOCATION	36	compound	-
35	Polyana	Polyana	NNP	O	33	nmod	-
36	''	''	''	O	33	punct	-
37	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	Companies	company	NNS	O	4	nsubj	0
1	may	may	MD	O	4	aux	-
2	also	also	RB	O	4	advmod	-
3	take	take	VB	O	0	ROOT	-
4	out	out	RP	O	4	compound:prt	-
5	strike	strike	NN	O	7	compound	1
6	insurance	insurance	NN	O	4	dobj	-
7	prior	prior	RB	O	4	advmod	-
8	to	to	TO	O	12	case	-
9	an	a	DT	O	12	det	-
10	anticipated	anticipated	JJ	O	12	amod	-
11	strike	strike	NN	O	8	nmod	0
12	,	,	,	O	4	punct	-
13	to	to	TO	O	15	mark	-
14	help	help	VB	O	4	xcomp	0
15	offset	offset	VB	O	15	ccomp	-
16	the	the	DT	O	18	det	-
17	losses	loss	NNS	O	16	dobj	0
18	which	which	WDT	O	23	dobj	-
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	strike	strike	NN	O	23	nsubj	-
21	would	would	MD	O	23	aux	-
22	cause	cause	VB	O	18	acl:relcl	-
23	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	4	det	-
1	most	most	RBS	O	3	advmod	1
2	common	common	JJ	O	4	amod	1
3	reason	reason	NN	O	12	nsubj	-
4	for	for	IN	O	6	mark	1
5	erecting	erect	VBG	O	4	acl	-
6	a	a	DT	O	8	det	0
7	khachkar	khachkar	NN	O	6	dobj	0
8	was	be	VBD	O	12	cop	-
9	for	for	IN	O	12	case	0
10	votive	votive	JJ	O	12	amod	-
11	reasons	reason	NNS	O	0	ROOT	0
12	-	-	:	O	12	punct	0
13	for	for	IN	O	16	case	0
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
15	salvation	salvation	NN	O	12	nmod	0
16	of	of	IN	O	19	case	-
17	the	the	DT	O	19	det	0
18	soul	soul	NN	O	16	nmod	-
19	of	of	IN	O	23	case	1
20	either	either	CC	O	23	cc:preconj	0
21	a	a	DT	O	23	det	0
22	living	living	NN	O	19	nmod	0
23	or	or	CC	O	23	cc	0
24	a	a	DT	O	27	det	-
25	deceased	deceased	JJ	O	27	amod	-
26	person	person	NN	O	23	conj	-
27	.	.	.	O	12	punct	-

0	Scene	scene	NN	O	0	ROOT	-
1	2	2	CD	NUMBER	1	nummod	0
2	:	:	:	O	1	punct	-
3	The	the	DT	O	5	det	1
4	Doctor	doctor	NN	O	6	nsubj	-
5	rushes	rush	VBZ	O	1	dep	-
6	by	by	IN	O	9	case	0
7	the	the	DT	O	9	det	0
8	Captain	Captain	NNP	O	6	nmod	0
9	in	in	IN	O	12	case	-
10	the	the	DT	O	12	det	0
11	street	street	NN	O	6	nmod	-
12	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
13	who	who	WP	O	15	nsubj	-
14	urges	urge	VBZ	O	6	ccomp	-
15	him	he	PRP	O	15	dobj	0
16	to	to	TO	O	18	mark	-
17	slow	slow	VB	O	15	xcomp	-
18	down	down	RP	O	18	compound:prt	0
19	.	.	.	O	1	punct	0

0	A	a	DT	O	3	det	-
1	carotenoid	carotenoid	NN	O	3	compound	-
2	dye	dye	VB	O	7	nsubj	-
3	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
4	crocin	crocin	NN	O	3	appos	-
5	,	,	,	O	3	punct	0
6	allows	allow	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
7	saffron	saffron	NN	O	7	dobj	0
8	to	to	TO	O	10	mark	0
9	impart	impart	VB	O	7	xcomp	-
10	a	a	DT	O	14	det	-
11	rich	rich	JJ	O	14	amod	-
12	golden-yellow	golden-yellow	JJ	O	14	amod	-
13	hue	hue	NN	O	10	dobj	-
14	to	to	TO	O	16	case	-
15	dishes	dish	NNS	O	14	nmod	-
16	and	and	CC	O	16	cc	-
17	textiles	textile	NNS	O	16	conj	-
18	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-
19	Saffron	Saffron	NNP	O	21	nsubj	0
20	has	have	VBZ	O	7	parataxis	0
21	further	further	RB	O	24	advmod	1
22	medicinal	medicinal	JJ	O	24	amod	0
23	applications	application	NNS	O	21	dobj	-
24	.	.	.	O	7	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	revival	revival	NN	O	9	nsubj	-
2	of	of	IN	O	4	case	1
3	lute	lute	NN	O	2	nmod	-
4	in	in	IN	O	8	case	-
5	the	the	DT	DATE	8	det	-
6	20th	20th	JJ	DATE	8	amod	-
7	century	century	NN	DATE	2	nmod	-
8	revitalized	revitalize	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
9	the	the	DT	O	11	det	1
10	interest	interest	NN	O	9	dobj	-
11	of	of	IN	O	13	case	0
12	composers	composer	NNS	O	11	nmod	1
13	in	in	IN	O	16	case	-
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
15	instruments	instrument	NNS	O	11	nmod	-
16	of	of	IN	O	20	case	0
17	the	the	DT	O	20	det	-
18	lute	lute	NN	O	20	compound	0
19	family	family	NN	O	16	nmod	0
20	.	.	.	O	9	punct	0

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	1
1	2006	2006	CD	DATE	6	nmod	-
2	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
3	Nippon	Nippon	NNP	PERSON	5	compound	0
4	Ichi	Ichi	NNP	PERSON	6	nsubj	-
5	released	release	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
6	a	a	DT	O	8	det	0
7	sequel	sequel	NN	O	6	dobj	0
8	called	call	VBN	O	8	acl	-
9	for	for	IN	O	13	case	0
10	the	the	DT	O	13	det	-
11	PlayStation	PlayStation	NNP	O	13	compound	0
12	2	2	CD	NUMBER	9	nmod	-
13	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
14	as	as	RB	O	8	cc	-
15	well	well	RB	O	15	mwe	-
16	as	as	IN	O	15	mwe	-
17	a	a	DT	O	20	det	-
18	12	12	CD	NUMBER	20	nummod	-
19	episode	episode	NN	O	8	conj	-
20	long	long	JJ	O	22	amod	-
21	anime	anime	NN	O	20	dep	-
22	titled	title	VBN	O	22	acl	-
23	Makai	Makai	NNP	O	26	compound	-
24	Senki	Senki	NNP	O	26	compound	-
25	Disgaea	Disgaea	NNP	O	23	xcomp	-
26	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	False	false	JJ	O	3	amod	-
2	gharial	gharial	NN	O	0	ROOT	-
3	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
4	also	also	RB	O	6	advmod	0
5	known	know	VBN	O	3	acl	0
6	as	as	IN	O	10	case	-
7	the	the	DT	O	10	det	1
8	Malayan	Malayan	NNP	MISC	10	compound	-
9	gharial	gharial	NN	O	6	nmod	0
10	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
11	false	false	JJ	O	13	amod	0
12	gavial	gavial	JJ	O	20	nsubj	-
13	,	,	,	O	13	punct	0
14	or	or	CC	O	13	cc	0
15	Tomistoma	Tomistoma	NNP	O	13	conj	-
16	is	be	VBZ	O	20	cop	0
17	a	a	DT	O	20	det	-
18	fresh-water	fresh-water	JJ	O	20	amod	-
19	reptile	reptile	NN	O	3	acl:relcl	-
20	resembling	resemble	VBG	O	20	acl	0
21	a	a	DT	O	23	det	-
22	crocodile	crocodile	NN	O	21	dobj	0
23	with	with	IN	O	30	case	-
24	a	a	DT	O	30	det	-
25	very	very	RB	O	27	advmod	-
26	thin	thin	JJ	O	30	amod	-
27	and	and	CC	O	27	cc	-
28	elongated	elongate	VBN	O	27	conj	-
29	snout	snout	NN	O	23	nmod	-
30	,	,	,	O	30	punct	-
31	which	which	WDT	O	34	nsubj	-
32	is	be	VBZ	O	34	cop	-
33	thicker	thicker	JJR	O	30	acl:relcl	-
34	than	than	IN	O	37	case	-
35	the	the	DT	O	37	det	-
36	gharial	gharial	NN	O	34	nmod	-
37	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	Efferent	efferent	JJ	O	3	amod	0
1	neuron	neuron	NN	O	3	compound	-
2	s	s	NNS	O	4	nsubj	-
3	transmit	transmit	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
4	signals	signal	NNS	O	4	dobj	0
5	from	from	IN	O	10	case	-
6	the	the	DT	O	10	det	0
7	central	central	JJ	O	10	amod	-
8	nervous	nervous	JJ	O	10	amod	-
9	system	system	NN	O	5	nmod	0
10	to	to	TO	O	16	case	0
11	the	the	DT	O	16	det	-
12	effector	effector	NN	O	16	compound	-
13	cell	cell	NN	O	16	compound	-
14	s.	s.	NN	O	16	compound	-
15	Interneuron	Interneuron	NNP	ORGANIZATION	10	nmod	0
16	s	s	VBZ	O	5	dep	0
17	connect	connect	VB	O	17	acl	0
18	neurons	neuron	NNS	O	18	dobj	0
19	within	within	IN	O	24	case	0
20	the	the	DT	O	24	det	-
21	central	central	JJ	O	24	amod	0
22	nervous	nervous	JJ	O	24	amod	-
23	system	system	NN	O	18	nmod	0
24	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	featured	feature	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
1	a	a	DT	O	4	det	0
2	live-action	live-action	JJ	O	4	amod	1
3	series	series	NN	O	1	dobj	-
4	of	of	IN	O	6	case	-
5	skits	skit	NNS	O	4	nmod	-
6	starring	star	VBG	O	6	acl	-
7	former	former	JJ	O	10	amod	-
8	WWF	WWF	NNP	ORGANIZATION	10	compound	0
9	manager	manager	NN	O	7	dobj	0
10	``	``	``	O	15	punct	0
11	Captain	Captain	NNP	O	15	compound	-
12	''	''	''	O	15	punct	0
13	Lou	Lou	NNP	PERSON	15	compound	-
14	Albano	Albano	NNP	PERSON	10	nmod	0
15	as	as	IN	O	17	case	1
16	Mario	Mario	NNP	PERSON	15	nmod	-
17	and	and	CC	O	17	cc	-
18	Danny	Danny	NNP	PERSON	20	compound	-
19	Wells	Wells	NNP	PERSON	17	conj	0
20	as	as	IN	O	22	case	0
21	Luigi	Luigi	NNP	PERSON	15	nmod	-
22	.	.	.	O	1	punct	-

0	February	February	NNP	DATE	0	ROOT	0
1	18	18	CD	DATE	1	nummod	-
2	-	-	:	O	1	punct	-
3	A	a	DT	O	5	det	0
4	train	train	NN	O	1	dep	0
5	carrying	carry	VBG	O	5	acl	-
6	a	a	DT	O	8	det	0
7	convoy	convoy	NN	O	15	nsubj	-
8	of	of	IN	O	10	case	0
9	petrol	petrol	NN	O	8	nmod	0
10	,	,	,	O	10	punct	0
11	fertiliser	fertiliser	NN	O	10	conj	-
12	and	and	CC	O	10	cc	0
13	sulphur	sulphur	NN	O	10	conj	-
14	derails	derail	NNS	O	6	dobj	0
15	and	and	CC	O	15	cc	0
16	explodes	explode	VBZ	O	15	conj	0
17	in	in	IN	O	19	case	-
18	Iran	Iran	NNP	LOCATION	15	nmod	-
19	,	,	,	O	1	punct	0
20	killing	kill	VBG	O	1	acl	0
21	320	320	CD	NUMBER	23	nummod	-
22	people	people	NNS	O	21	dobj	-
23	.	.	.	O	1	punct	0

0	Fossil	fossil	JJ	O	2	amod	0
1	fuels	fuel	NNS	O	5	nsubj	-
2	are	be	VBP	O	5	cop	-
3	fuel	fuel	NN	O	5	compound	-
4	s	s	NNS	O	0	ROOT	0
5	from	from	IN	O	8	case	-
6	fossil	fossil	JJ	O	8	amod	-
7	s.	s.	NNS	O	5	nmod	-
8	The	the	DT	O	13	det	-
9	three	three	CD	NUMBER	13	nummod	0
10	most	most	RBS	O	12	advmod	-
11	important	important	JJ	O	13	amod	-
12	fossils	fossil	NNS	O	8	dep	0
13	fuels	fuel	NNS	O	16	nsubj	0
14	are	be	VBP	O	16	cop	-
15	coal	coal	NN	O	13	acl:relcl	0
16	,	,	,	O	16	punct	-
17	petroleum	petroleum	NN	O	16	conj	0
18	,	,	,	O	16	punct	0
19	and	and	CC	O	16	cc	-
20	natural	natural	JJ	O	22	amod	1
21	gas	gas	NN	O	16	conj	-
22	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	Mozart	Mozart	NNP	PERSON	2	nsubj	-
1	began	begin	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
2	a	a	DT	O	4	det	-
3	series	series	NN	O	2	dobj	-
4	of	of	IN	O	6	case	-
5	concerts	concert	NNS	O	4	nmod	-
6	in	in	IN	O	8	case	-
7	which	which	WDT	O	10	nmod	0
8	he	he	PRP	O	10	nsubj	0
9	played	play	VBD	O	6	acl:relcl	-
10	his	he	PRP$	O	15	nmod:poss	0
11	own	own	JJ	O	15	amod	-
12	piano	piano	NN	O	15	compound	0
13	concerto	concerto	NN	O	15	compound	-
14	s	s	NNS	O	10	dobj	0
15	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
16	conducting	conduct	VBG	O	2	advcl	0
17	from	from	IN	O	20	case	-
18	the	the	DT	O	20	det	0
19	keyboard	keyboard	NN	O	17	nmod	-
20	.	.	.	O	2	punct	0

0	Nowadays	nowadays	RB	O	5	advmod	0
1	this	this	DT	O	5	nsubjpass	0
2	would	would	MD	O	5	aux	-
3	be	be	VB	O	5	auxpass	-
4	called	call	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
5	``	``	``	O	5	punct	-
6	exploiting	exploit	VBG	O	5	xcomp	-
7	''	''	''	O	7	punct	0
8	the	the	DT	O	11	det	0
9	young	young	JJ	O	11	amod	0
10	genius	genius	NN	O	7	dobj	-
11	,	,	,	O	11	punct	1
12	but	but	CC	O	11	cc	-
13	in	in	IN	O	17	case	-
14	those	those	DT	O	17	det	0
15	days	day	NNS	DURATION	17	compound	-
16	people	people	NNS	O	11	conj	0
17	saw	see	VBD	O	17	acl	-
18	nothing	nothing	NN	O	18	dobj	0
19	wrong	wrong	JJ	O	19	amod	-
20	with	with	IN	O	22	mark	-
21	allowing	allow	VBG	O	18	advcl	-
22	a	a	DT	O	24	det	-
23	child	child	NN	O	22	dobj	0
24	to	to	TO	O	27	mark	0
25	be	be	VB	O	27	auxpass	-
26	used	use	VBN	O	22	xcomp	0
27	in	in	IN	O	30	case	0
28	this	this	DT	O	30	det	-
29	way	way	NN	O	27	nmod	0
30	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	first	first	JJ	ORDINAL	3	amod	-
2	amniotes	amniote	NNS	O	9	nsubj	0
3	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
4	such	such	JJ	O	7	case	-
5	as	as	IN	O	5	mwe	-
6	Casineria	Casineria	NNP	LOCATION	3	nmod	-
7	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
8	resembled	resemble	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
9	small	small	JJ	O	11	amod	-
10	lizards	lizard	NNS	O	9	dobj	-
11	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
12	evolved	evolve	VBD	O	9	conj	-
13	from	from	IN	O	16	case	-
14	amphibian	amphibian	JJ	O	16	amod	-
15	reptiliomorphs	reptiliomorph	NNS	O	13	nmod	0
16	about	about	IN	DATE	19	advmod	-
17	340	340	CD	DATE	19	compound	-
18	million	million	CD	DATE	20	nummod	-
19	years	year	NNS	DATE	21	nmod:npmod	-
20	ago	ago	RB	DATE	13	advmod	-
21	.	.	.	O	9	punct	-

0	Typically	typically	RB	O	13	advmod	-
1	,	,	,	O	13	punct	0
2	the	the	DT	O	5	det	0
3	biggest	biggest	JJS	O	5	amod	-
4	difference	difference	NN	O	13	nsubj	0
5	between	between	IN	O	7	case	-
6	film	film	NN	O	5	nmod	0
7	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	0
8	stage	stage	NN	O	10	compound	-
9	musicals	musical	NNS	O	7	conj	-
10	is	be	VBZ	O	13	cop	-
11	the	the	DT	O	13	det	0
12	use	use	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
13	of	of	IN	O	17	case	-
14	lavish	lavish	JJ	O	17	amod	0
15	background	background	NN	O	17	compound	-
16	scenery	scenery	NN	O	13	nmod	0
17	which	which	WDT	O	21	nsubj	0
18	would	would	MD	O	21	aux	-
19	be	be	VB	O	21	cop	0
20	impractical	impractical	JJ	O	17	acl:relcl	-
21	in	in	IN	O	24	case	0
22	a	a	DT	O	24	det	-
23	theater	theater	NN	O	21	nmod	0
24	.	.	.	O	13	punct	-

0	Historically	Historically	NNP	O	14	nsubj	0
1	,	,	,	O	14	punct	0
2	in	in	IN	O	6	case	0
3	the	the	DT	O	6	det	0
4	warm	warm	JJ	O	6	amod	-
5	Mediterranean	Mediterranean	NNP	LOCATION	14	nmod	0
6	and	and	CC	O	6	cc	0
7	Middle	Middle	NNP	MISC	10	compound	0
8	Eastern	Eastern	NNP	MISC	10	compound	-
9	climates	climate	NNS	O	6	conj	-
10	,	,	,	O	14	punct	0
11	the	the	DT	O	13	det	-
12	courtyard	courtyard	NN	O	14	nsubj	0
13	served	serve	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
14	to	to	TO	O	16	mark	0
15	accommodate	accommodate	VB	O	14	xcomp	0
16	the	the	DT	O	19	det	0
17	large	large	JJ	O	19	amod	0
18	number	number	NN	O	16	dobj	0
19	of	of	IN	O	21	case	-
20	worshippers	worshipper	NNS	O	19	nmod	0
21	during	during	IN	O	24	case	-
22	Friday	Friday	NNP	DATE	24	compound	-
23	prayers	prayer	NNS	O	16	nmod	0
24	.	.	.	O	14	punct	0

0	In	in	IN	O	2	case	0
1	1999	1999	CD	DATE	9	nmod	0
2	,	,	,	O	9	punct	0
3	a	a	DT	O	7	det	0
4	World	World	NNP	ORGANIZATION	7	compound	-
5	Tamil	Tamil	NNP	ORGANIZATION	7	compound	-
6	Confederation	Confederation	NNP	ORGANIZATION	9	nsubjpass	0
7	was	be	VBD	O	9	auxpass	-
8	established	establish	VBN	O	0	ROOT	0
9	to	to	TO	O	11	mark	0
10	protect	protect	VB	O	9	xcomp	-
11	and	and	CC	O	11	cc	-
12	foster	foster	VB	O	11	conj	0
13	Tamil	tamil	JJ	MISC	15	amod	0
14	culture	culture	NN	O	11	dobj	-
15	and	and	CC	O	11	cc	0
16	further	further	RB	O	19	advmod	0
17	a	a	DT	O	19	det	-
18	sense	sense	NN	O	11	conj	-
19	of	of	IN	O	21	case	0
20	togetherness	togetherness	NN	O	19	nmod	0
21	amongst	amongst	IN	O	23	case	-
22	Tamils	Tamils	NNPS	MISC	19	nmod	0
23	in	in	IN	O	26	case	-
24	different	different	JJ	O	26	amod	0
25	countries	country	NNS	O	23	nmod	0
26	.	.	.	O	9	punct	0

0	Throughout	throughout	IN	O	2	case	0
1	most	most	JJS	O	19	nmod	0
2	of	of	IN	O	5	case	0
3	the	the	DT	O	5	det	-
4	film	film	NN	O	2	nmod	0
5	,	,	,	O	19	punct	-
6	his	he	PRP$	O	10	nmod:poss	-
7	only	only	RB	O	10	advmod	0
8	true	true	JJ	O	10	amod	-
9	friend	friend	NN	O	19	nsubj	0
10	,	,	,	O	10	punct	0
11	aside	aside	RB	O	10	advmod	-
12	from	from	IN	O	15	case	-
13	his	he	PRP$	O	15	nmod:poss	0
14	mother	mother	NN	O	12	nmod	0
15	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
16	is	be	VBZ	O	19	cop	-
17	the	the	DT	O	19	det	-
18	mouse	mouse	NN	O	0	ROOT	-
19	,	,	,	O	19	punct	0
20	Timothy	Timothy	NNP	PERSON	19	appos	0
21	-	-	:	O	21	punct	0
22	a	a	DT	O	24	det	-
23	relationship	relationship	NN	O	21	dep	0
24	parodying	parody	VBG	O	24	acl	0
25	the	the	DT	O	28	det	-
26	stereotypical	stereotypical	JJ	O	28	amod	-
27	animosity	animosity	NN	O	25	dobj	0
28	between	between	IN	O	30	case	-
29	mice	mouse	NNS	O	28	nmod	0
30	and	and	CC	O	30	cc	0
31	elephants	elephant	NNS	O	30	conj	0
32	.	.	.	O	19	punct	0

0	John	John	NNP	PERSON	2	compound	-
1	McCain	McCain	NNP	PERSON	3	nsubj	-
2	polled	poll	VBN	O	0	ROOT	-
3	62.5	62.5	CD	PERCENT	5	nummod	-
4	%	%	NN	PERCENT	3	dobj	-
5	in	in	IN	O	10	case	-
6	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
7	2008	2008	CD	DATE	10	nummod	0
8	Presidential	Presidential	NNP	O	10	compound	-
9	Election	Election	NNP	O	3	nmod	-
10	while	while	IN	O	16	mark	0
11	70.9	70.9	CD	PERCENT	13	nummod	-
12	%	%	NN	PERCENT	16	nsubj	-
13	of	of	IN	O	15	case	-
14	Utahns	Utahns	NNPS	MISC	13	nmod	-
15	opted	opt	VBD	O	3	advcl	-
16	for	for	IN	O	20	case	0
17	George	George	NNP	PERSON	20	compound	-
18	W.	W.	NNP	PERSON	20	compound	-
19	Bush	Bush	NNP	PERSON	16	nmod	0
20	in	in	IN	O	22	case	-
21	2004	2004	CD	DATE	16	nmod	-
22	.	.	.	O	3	punct	0

0	His	he	PRP$	O	3	nmod:poss	-
1	linguistic	linguistic	JJ	O	3	amod	0
2	capacity	capacity	NN	O	8	nsubj	0
3	,	,	,	O	3	punct	0
4	thoughts	thought	NNS	O	3	conj	-
5	and	and	CC	O	3	cc	-
6	speeches	speech	NNS	O	3	conj	-
7	correspond	correspond	VBP	O	0	ROOT	0
8	to	to	TO	O	10	case	0
9	those	those	DT	O	8	nmod	-
10	of	of	IN	O	13	case	0
11	modern	modern	JJ	O	13	amod	-
12	man	man	NN	O	10	nmod	-
13	,	,	,	O	10	punct	-
14	including	include	VBG	O	18	case	0
15	a	a	DT	O	18	det	0
16	vast	vast	JJ	O	18	amod	0
17	knowledge	knowledge	NN	O	10	nmod	-
18	about	about	IN	O	20	case	0
19	history	history	NN	O	18	nmod	0
20	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
21	politics	politics	NNS	O	20	conj	0
22	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
23	philosophy	philosophy	NN	O	20	conj	-
24	and	and	CC	O	20	cc	-
25	literature	literature	NN	O	20	conj	-
26	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	Digital	Digital	NNP	O	2	compound	-
1	signatures	signature	NNS	O	4	nsubj	-
2	are	be	VBP	O	4	cop	0
3	equivalent	equivalent	JJ	O	0	ROOT	0
4	to	to	TO	O	8	case	-
5	traditional	traditional	JJ	O	8	amod	0
6	handwritten	handwritten	JJ	O	8	amod	-
7	signatures	signature	NNS	O	4	nmod	0
8	in	in	IN	O	11	case	-
9	many	many	JJ	O	11	amod	-
10	respects	respects	NNS	O	8	nmod	-
11	;	;	:	O	4	punct	-
12	properly	properly	RB	O	14	advmod	-
13	implemented	implement	VBN	O	16	amod	0
14	digital	digital	JJ	O	16	amod	0
15	signatures	signature	NNS	O	19	nsubj	-
16	are	be	VBP	O	19	cop	-
17	more	more	RBR	O	19	advmod	0
18	difficult	difficult	JJ	O	4	parataxis	-
19	to	to	TO	O	21	mark	-
20	forge	forge	VB	O	19	xcomp	-
21	than	than	IN	O	25	case	-
22	the	the	DT	O	25	det	-
23	handwritten	handwritten	JJ	O	25	amod	-
24	type	type	NN	O	21	nmod	0
25	.	.	.	O	4	punct	0

0	Polar	Polar	NNP	O	3	compound	-
1	bear	bear	NN	O	3	compound	0
2	fur	fur	NN	O	4	nsubj	-
3	consists	consist	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
4	of	of	IN	O	7	case	0
5	a	a	DT	O	7	det	-
6	layer	layer	NN	O	4	nmod	0
7	of	of	IN	O	10	case	-
8	dense	dense	JJ	O	10	amod	0
9	underfur	underfur	NN	O	7	nmod	0
10	and	and	CC	O	10	cc	-
11	an	a	DT	O	14	det	-
12	outer	outer	JJ	O	14	amod	-
13	layer	layer	NN	O	10	conj	-
14	of	of	IN	O	17	case	0
15	guard	guard	NN	O	17	compound	-
16	hairs	hair	NNS	O	14	nmod	-
17	,	,	,	O	7	punct	-
18	which	which	WDT	O	20	nsubj	0
19	appear	appear	VBP	O	7	acl:relcl	0
20	white	white	JJ	O	20	xcomp	-
21	to	to	TO	O	23	case	-
22	tan	tan	NN	O	21	nmod	-
23	but	but	CC	O	20	cc	-
24	are	be	VBP	O	27	cop	-
25	actually	actually	RB	O	27	advmod	-
26	transparent	transparent	JJ	O	20	conj	-
27	.	.	.	O	4	punct	-

0	Recent	recent	JJ	O	3	amod	-
1	archaeological	archaeological	JJ	O	3	amod	0
2	evidence	evidence	NN	O	5	nsubj	-
3	may	may	MD	O	5	aux	-
4	indicate	indicate	VB	O	0	ROOT	-
5	an	a	DT	O	8	det	-
6	Edomite	edomite	JJ	MISC	8	amod	-
7	nation	nation	NN	O	5	dobj	-
8	as	as	IN	O	11	case	-
9	long	long	JJ	O	11	amod	-
10	ago	ago	RB	O	5	advcl	-
11	as	as	IN	O	16	mark	-
12	the	the	DT	DATE	15	det	-
13	11th	11th	JJ	DATE	15	amod	-
14	century	century	NN	DATE	16	nsubj	-
15	BC	BC	NNP	DATE	11	dep	-
16	,	,	,	O	16	punct	0
17	but	but	CC	O	16	cc	0
18	the	the	DT	O	20	det	-
19	topic	topic	NN	O	22	nsubj	-
20	is	be	VBZ	O	22	cop	0
21	controversial	controversial	JJ	O	16	conj	0
22	and	and	CC	O	22	cc	-
23	others	other	NNS	O	25	nsubj	-
24	argue	argue	VBP	O	22	conj	-
25	that	that	IN	O	34	mark	-
26	the	the	DT	O	32	det	-
27	8th	8th	JJ	ORDINAL	32	amod	-
28	or	or	CC	O	28	cc	-
29	9th	9th	JJ	DATE	28	conj	-
30	century	century	NN	DATE	32	compound	-
31	dates	date	NNS	O	34	nsubj	-
32	are	be	VBP	O	34	cop	-
33	correct	correct	JJ	O	25	ccomp	-
34	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	8	mark	0
1	the	the	DT	O	3	det	0
2	1950	1950	CD	DATE	8	dep	-
3	's	's	POS	O	3	case	-
4	,	,	,	O	8	punct	0
5	Erwin	Erwin	NNP	PERSON	7	compound	-
6	Chargaff	Chargaff	NNP	PERSON	8	nsubj	-
7	discovered	discover	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
8	that	that	IN	O	25	mark	-
9	the	the	DT	O	11	det	0
10	amount	amount	NN	O	25	nsubj	-
11	of	of	IN	O	15	case	-
12	Thymine	Thymine	NNP	O	15	compound	-
13	(	(	CD	NUMBER	15	nummod	0
14	T	t	NN	O	11	nmod	0
15	)	)	CD	NUMBER	15	nummod	-
16	present	present	JJ	DATE	15	amod	0
17	in	in	IN	O	20	case	0
18	a	a	DT	O	20	det	0
19	molecule	molecule	NN	O	11	nmod	-
20	of	of	IN	O	22	case	0
21	DNA	dna	NN	MISC	20	nmod	-
22	was	be	VBD	O	25	cop	-
23	roughly	roughly	RB	O	25	advmod	0
24	equal	equal	JJ	O	8	ccomp	-
25	to	to	TO	O	28	case	0
26	the	the	DT	O	28	det	-
27	amount	amount	NN	O	25	nmod	-
28	of	of	IN	O	30	case	-
29	Adenine	Adenine	NNP	LOCATION	28	nmod	-
30	(	(	CD	NUMBER	33	nummod	-
31	A	a	DT	O	33	det	-
32	)	)	NN	O	30	dep	-
33	present	present	JJ	DATE	33	amod	-
34	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	There	there	EX	O	2	expl	-
1	are	be	VBP	O	0	ROOT	-
2	several	several	JJ	O	4	amod	0
3	stories	story	NNS	O	2	nsubj	0
4	about	about	IN	O	9	case	-
5	Mozart	Mozart	NNP	PERSON	9	nmod:poss	-
6	's	's	POS	O	6	case	-
7	final	final	JJ	O	9	amod	0
8	illness	illness	NN	O	4	nmod	0
9	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
10	death	death	NN	O	9	conj	-
11	,	,	,	O	2	punct	-
12	and	and	CC	O	2	cc	-
13	it	it	PRP	O	17	nsubj	-
14	is	be	VBZ	O	17	cop	-
15	not	not	RB	O	17	neg	-
16	easy	easy	JJ	O	2	conj	-
17	to	to	TO	O	20	mark	-
18	be	be	VB	O	20	cop	0
19	sure	sure	JJ	O	17	xcomp	0
20	what	what	WP	O	22	nsubj	-
21	happened	happen	VBD	O	20	ccomp	0
22	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	0
1	Pope	Pope	NNP	O	6	nsubj	-
2	is	be	VBZ	O	6	cop	0
3	also	also	RB	O	6	advmod	0
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	head	head	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
6	of	of	IN	O	8	case	-
7	state	state	NN	O	6	nmod	0
8	of	of	IN	O	11	case	0
9	Vatican	Vatican	NNP	LOCATION	11	compound	-
10	City	City	NNP	LOCATION	8	nmod	0
11	,	,	,	O	6	punct	-
12	a	a	DT	O	15	det	0
13	tiny	tiny	JJ	O	15	amod	-
14	country	country	NN	O	6	appos	-
15	in	in	IN	O	18	case	0
16	the	the	DT	O	18	det	0
17	city	city	NN	O	15	nmod	0
18	of	of	IN	O	20	case	-
19	Rome	Rome	NNP	LOCATION	18	nmod	0
20	in	in	IN	O	22	case	-
21	Italy	Italy	NNP	LOCATION	18	nmod	0
22	,	,	,	O	18	punct	0
23	whose	whose	WP$	O	26	nmod:poss	-
24	sole	sole	JJ	O	26	amod	-
25	purpose	purpose	NN	O	27	nsubj	-
26	is	be	VBZ	O	18	acl:relcl	-
27	to	to	TO	O	29	mark	-
28	run	run	VB	O	27	xcomp	-
29	the	the	DT	O	33	det	-
30	Roman	Roman	NNP	ORGANIZATION	33	compound	-
31	Catholic	Catholic	NNP	ORGANIZATION	33	compound	-
32	Church	Church	NNP	ORGANIZATION	29	dobj	-
33	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	Canberra	Canberra	NNP	LOCATION	5	nsubj	-
1	is	be	VBZ	O	5	cop	-
2	an	a	DT	O	5	det	0
3	Aboriginal	aboriginal	JJ	MISC	5	amod	-
4	name	name	NN	O	0	ROOT	-
5	which	which	WDT	O	7	nsubj	-
6	means	mean	VBZ	O	5	acl:relcl	-
7	`'	`'	CD	NUMBER	10	nummod	0
8	Meeting	meet	VBG	O	10	compound	1
9	point	point	NN	O	7	dobj	0
10	''	''	''	O	7	punct	-
11	and	and	CC	O	7	cc	-
12	you	you	PRP	O	15	nsubj	-
13	can	can	MD	O	15	aux	0
14	pronounce	pronounce	VB	O	7	conj	0
15	it	it	PRP	O	15	dobj	-
16	in	in	IN	O	20	case	-
17	many	many	JJ	O	20	amod	-
18	different	different	JJ	O	20	amod	-
19	ways	way	NNS	O	15	nmod	-
20	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	He	he	PRP	O	2	nsubj	0
1	wrote	write	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
2	Pale	Pale	NNP	O	5	compound	-
3	Blue	Blue	NNP	O	5	compound	-
4	Dot	Dot	NNP	O	2	dobj	0
5	:	:	:	O	5	punct	-
6	A	A	NNP	O	8	compound	0
7	Vision	Vision	NNP	O	5	dep	-
8	of	of	IN	O	12	case	-
9	the	the	DT	O	12	det	0
10	Human	human	JJ	O	12	amod	0
11	Future	Future	NNP	DATE	8	nmod	-
12	in	in	IN	O	14	case	-
13	Space	Space	NNP	O	12	nmod	-
14	,	,	,	O	14	punct	-
15	which	which	WDT	O	18	nsubjpass	-
16	was	be	VBD	O	18	auxpass	-
17	selected	select	VBN	O	14	acl:relcl	-
18	as	as	IN	O	22	case	0
19	a	a	DT	O	22	det	-
20	notable	notable	JJ	O	22	amod	1
21	book	book	NN	O	18	nmod	-
22	of	of	IN	O	24	case	0
23	1995	1995	CD	DATE	22	nmod	-
24	by	by	IN	O	29	case	-
25	The	the	DT	O	29	det	-
26	New	New	NNP	ORGANIZATION	29	compound	0
27	York	York	NNP	ORGANIZATION	29	compound	-
28	Times	Times	NNP	ORGANIZATION	22	nmod	-
29	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	Others	other	NNS	O	2	nsubj	-
1	call	call	VBP	O	0	ROOT	-
2	this	this	DT	O	6	det	-
3	`	`	``	O	6	punct	-
4	State	state	NN	O	6	compound	-
5	Socialism	socialism	NN	O	2	dobj	-
6	'	'	''	O	6	punct	0
7	,	,	,	O	6	punct	-
8	to	to	TO	O	10	mark	-
9	distinguish	distinguish	VB	O	6	acl	0
10	it	it	PRP	O	10	dobj	0
11	from	from	IN	O	15	case	-
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	-
13	communist	communist	JJ	O	15	amod	0
14	goal	goal	NN	O	10	nmod	-
15	that	that	WDT	O	19	nsubj	-
16	does	do	VBZ	O	19	aux	0
17	n't	not	RB	O	19	neg	-
18	require	require	VB	O	15	acl:relcl	0
19	a	a	DT	O	21	det	-
20	state	state	NN	O	19	dobj	-
21	or	or	CC	O	21	cc	-
22	any	any	DT	O	24	det	-
23	form	form	NN	O	21	conj	-
24	of	of	IN	O	26	case	-
25	government	government	NN	O	24	nmod	-
26	.	.	.	O	2	punct	-

0	In	in	IN	O	4	case	0
1	a	a	DT	O	4	det	-
2	press	press	NN	O	4	compound	0
3	conference	conference	NN	O	20	nmod	-
4	in	in	IN	O	6	case	-
5	Baghdad	Baghdad	NNP	LOCATION	4	nmod	0
6	,	,	,	O	20	punct	0
7	shortly	shortly	RB	O	9	advmod	-
8	afterwards	afterwards	RB	O	20	advmod	0
9	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
10	the	the	DT	O	14	det	0
11	U.S.	U.S.	NNP	LOCATION	14	compound	0
12	Civil	civil	JJ	O	14	amod	-
13	Administrator	Administrator	NNP	O	20	nsubj	-
14	in	in	IN	O	16	case	-
15	Iraq	Iraq	NNP	LOCATION	20	nmod	-
16	Paul	Paul	NNP	PERSON	18	compound	-
17	Bremer	Bremer	NNP	PERSON	20	nsubj	-
18	formally	formally	RB	O	20	advmod	0
19	announced	announce	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
20	the	the	DT	O	22	det	-
21	capture	capture	NN	O	20	dobj	-
22	of	of	IN	O	24	case	-
23	Saddam	Saddam	NNP	PERSON	22	nmod	-
24	by	by	IN	O	26	mark	-
25	saying	say	VBG	O	20	advcl	-
26	,	,	,	O	26	punct	-
27	``	``	``	O	34	punct	-
28	Ladies	Ladies	NNP	O	34	ccomp	-
29	and	and	CC	O	29	cc	-
30	gentlemen	gentleman	NNS	O	29	conj	-
31	,	,	,	O	34	punct	-
32	we	we	PRP	O	34	nsubj	-
33	got	get	VBD	O	26	ccomp	-
34	him	he	PRP	O	34	nsubj	-
35	!	!	.	O	20	punct	-

0	Port	Port	NNP	PERSON	2	compound	-
1	Arthur	Arthur	NNP	PERSON	6	nsubj	-
2	was	be	VBD	O	6	cop	0
3	also	also	RB	O	6	advmod	-
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	destination	destination	NN	O	0	ROOT	0
6	for	for	IN	O	9	case	-
7	juvenile	juvenile	JJ	O	9	amod	-
8	convicts	convict	NNS	O	6	nmod	0
9	,	,	,	O	6	punct	0
10	receiving	receive	VBG	O	6	acl	-
11	many	many	JJ	O	13	amod	-
12	boys	boy	NNS	O	11	dobj	-
13	,	,	,	O	6	punct	-
14	some	some	DT	O	6	appos	-
15	as	as	IN	O	17	case	0
16	young	young	JJ	O	15	nmod	-
17	as	as	IN	O	19	case	-
18	nine	nine	CD	NUMBER	17	nmod	0
19	arrested	arrest	VBN	O	19	acl	0
20	for	for	IN	O	22	mark	0
21	stealing	steal	VBG	O	20	advcl	-
22	toys	toy	NNS	O	22	dobj	0
23	.	.	.	O	6	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	3	det	-
1	International	International	NNP	MISC	3	compound	0
2	re-formed	re-formed	JJ	O	20	nsubj	0
3	in	in	IN	O	5	case	-
4	1923	1923	CD	DATE	3	nmod	-
5	,	,	,	O	3	punct	-
6	and	and	CC	O	3	cc	-
7	was	be	VBD	O	9	auxpass	0
8	reconstituted	reconstitute	VBN	O	3	conj	-
9	again	again	RB	O	9	advmod	-
10	,	,	,	O	20	punct	-
11	in	in	IN	O	15	case	-
12	its	its	PRP$	O	15	nmod:poss	-
13	present	present	JJ	DATE	15	amod	-
14	form	form	NN	O	20	nmod	-
15	,	,	,	O	20	punct	0
16	after	after	IN	O	20	case	0
17	World	World	NNP	MISC	20	compound	-
18	War	War	NNP	MISC	20	compound	-
19	II	II	NNP	MISC	0	ROOT	-
20	.	.	.	O	20	punct	-

0	Long	Long	NNP	O	5	ccomp	-
1	ago	ago	RB	O	1	advmod	0
2	,	,	,	O	5	punct	0
3	there	there	EX	O	5	expl	0
4	was	be	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
5	a	a	DT	O	7	det	0
6	decision	decision	NN	O	5	nsubj	-
7	by	by	IN	O	13	case	0
8	the	the	DT	O	13	det	-
9	late	late	JJ	O	13	amod	0
10	former	former	JJ	O	13	amod	0
11	Prime	Prime	NNP	O	13	compound	-
12	Minister	Minister	NNP	O	7	nmod	-
13	,	,	,	O	13	punct	1
14	Rafik	Rafik	NNP	PERSON	16	compound	0
15	Hariri	Hariri	NNP	PERSON	13	appos	-
16	,	,	,	O	13	punct	0
17	to	to	TO	O	19	mark	-
18	restore	restore	VB	O	7	acl	1
19	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
20	synagogue	synagogue	NN	O	19	dobj	0
21	and	and	CC	O	19	cc	-
22	surround	surround	VB	O	19	conj	-
23	it	it	PRP	O	23	dobj	-
24	with	with	IN	O	27	case	-
25	a	a	DT	O	27	det	-
26	garden	garden	NN	O	23	nmod	0
27	.	.	.	O	5	punct	-

0	The	the	DT	O	2	det	-
1	Man	man	NN	O	7	nsubj	0
2	in	in	IN	O	6	case	0
3	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
4	High	high	JJ	O	6	amod	0
5	Castle	castle	NN	O	2	nmod	0
6	occurs	occur	VBZ	O	0	ROOT	-
7	in	in	IN	O	11	case	0
8	an	a	DT	O	11	det	-
9	alternate	alternate	JJ	O	11	amod	0
10	universe	universe	NN	O	7	nmod	-
11	United	United	NNP	LOCATION	13	compound	0
12	States	States	NNPS	LOCATION	14	nsubj	0
13	ruled	rule	VBD	O	11	acl:relcl	-
14	by	by	IN	O	19	case	-
15	the	the	DT	O	19	det	0
16	victorious	victorious	JJ	O	19	amod	-
17	Axis	Axis	NNP	MISC	19	compound	0
18	powers	power	NNS	O	14	nmod	-
19	.	.	.	O	7	punct	0

0	Progress	Progress	NNP	O	7	nsubjpass	-
1	in	in	IN	O	3	mark	0
2	developing	develop	VBG	O	1	acl	0
3	the	the	DT	O	5	det	-
4	TAR	tar	NN	O	3	dobj	-
5	was	be	VBD	O	7	auxpass	-
6	hindered	hinder	VBN	O	0	ROOT	-
7	by	by	IN	O	12	case	-
8	political	political	JJ	O	12	amod	0
9	and	and	CC	O	9	cc	-
10	economic	economic	JJ	O	9	conj	0
11	obstacles	obstacle	NNS	O	7	nmod	-
12	throughout	throughout	IN	O	15	case	0
13	the	the	DT	DATE	15	det	-
14	1960s	1960	NNS	DATE	12	nmod	-
15	,	,	,	O	15	punct	-
16	1970s	1970	NNS	DATE	15	conj	-
17	and	and	CC	O	15	cc	-
18	early	early	JJ	O	20	amod	0
19	1980s	1980	NNS	DATE	15	conj	-
20	.	.	.	O	7	punct	0

0	As	as	IN	O	3	case	0
1	a	a	DT	O	3	det	0
2	result	result	NN	O	16	nmod	0
3	of	of	IN	O	6	case	0
4	this	this	DT	O	6	det	0
5	acquisition	acquisition	NN	O	3	nmod	0
6	and	and	CC	O	3	cc	0
7	the	the	DT	O	10	det	-
8	legal	legal	JJ	O	10	amod	0
9	dispute	dispute	NN	O	3	conj	-
10	with	with	IN	O	13	case	0
11	Hearst	Hearst	NNP	ORGANIZATION	13	compound	0
12	Corporation	Corporation	NNP	ORGANIZATION	10	nmod	-
13	,	,	,	O	16	punct	-
14	Mandrakesoft	Mandrakesoft	NNP	ORGANIZATION	16	nsubj	0
15	announced	announce	VBD	O	0	ROOT	0
16	that	that	IN	O	24	mark	0
17	the	the	DT	O	21	det	-
18	new	new	JJ	O	21	amod	-
19	company	company	NN	O	21	compound	0
20	name	name	NN	O	24	nsubj	-
21	would	would	MD	O	24	aux	0
22	be	be	VB	O	24	cop	-
23	Mandriva	Mandriva	NNP	ORGANIZATION	16	ccomp	1
24	,	,	,	O	24	punct	-
25	and	and	CC	O	24	cc	-
26	that	that	IN	O	34	mark	0
27	Mandriva	Mandriva	NNP	ORGANIZATION	29	compound	-
28	Linux	Linux	NNP	ORGANIZATION	34	nsubj	-
29	would	would	MD	O	34	aux	-
30	be	be	VB	O	34	cop	-
31	the	the	DT	O	34	det	-
32	new	new	JJ	O	34	amod	-
33	name	name	NN	O	24	conj	-
34	covering	cover	VBG	O	34	acl	-
35	products	product	NNS	O	35	dobj	-
36	.	.	.	O	16	punct	-

0	He	he	PRP	O	3	nsubjpass	-
1	was	be	VBD	O	3	auxpass	-
2	born	bear	VBN	O	0	ROOT	-
3	at	at	IN	O	5	case	0
4	Plessiel	Plessiel	NNP	LOCATION	3	nmod	0
5	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
6	a	a	DT	O	8	det	-
7	hamlet	hamlet	NN	O	5	appos	0
8	of	of	IN	O	10	case	0
9	Drucat	drucat	NN	LOCATION	8	nmod	-
10	near	near	IN	O	12	case	-
11	Abbeville	Abbeville	NNP	LOCATION	10	nmod	-
12	,	,	,	O	5	punct	-
13	to	to	TO	O	17	case	-
14	a	a	DT	O	17	det	-
15	long-established	long-established	JJ	O	17	amod	-
16	family	family	NN	O	3	nmod	-
17	of	of	IN	O	19	case	-
18	Picardy	Picardy	NNP	LOCATION	17	nmod	-
19	,	,	,	O	17	punct	-
20	the	the	DT	O	22	det	-
21	great-nephew	great-nephew	NN	O	17	appos	-
22	of	of	IN	O	28	case	-
23	the	the	DT	O	28	det	-
24	painter	painter	NN	O	28	compound	-
25	Eustache	Eustache	NNP	PERSON	28	compound	-
26	Le	Le	NNP	PERSON	28	compound	-
27	Sueur	Sueur	NNP	PERSON	22	nmod	-
28	.	.	.	O	3	punct	-

0	To	to	TO	O	2	mark	-
1	enjoy	enjoy	VB	O	8	advcl	-
2	qin	qin	NN	O	4	compound	0
3	songs	song	NNS	O	2	dobj	0
4	,	,	,	O	8	punct	-
5	one	one	CD	NUMBER	8	nsubj	0
6	must	must	MD	O	8	aux	0
7	learn	learn	VB	O	0	ROOT	-
8	to	to	TO	O	10	mark	-
9	become	become	VB	O	8	xcomp	0
10	accustomed	accustomed	JJ	O	10	xcomp	-
11	to	to	TO	O	15	case	0
12	the	the	DT	O	15	det	0
13	eccentric	eccentric	JJ	O	15	amod	0
14	style	style	NN	O	19	nmod	-
15	some	some	DT	O	17	det	0
16	players	player	NNS	O	19	nsubj	0
17	may	may	MD	O	19	aux	-
18	sing	sing	VB	O	10	advcl	-
19	their	they	PRP$	O	21	nmod:poss	-
20	songs	song	NNS	O	19	dobj	0
21	to	to	TO	O	19	dep	0
22	,	,	,	O	22	punct	0
23	like	like	IN	O	27	case	0
24	in	in	IN	O	27	case	-
25	the	the	DT	O	27	det	0
26	case	case	NN	O	23	nmod	-
27	of	of	IN	O	30	case	0
28	Zha	Zha	NNP	PERSON	30	compound	-
29	Fuxi	Fuxi	NNP	PERSON	27	nmod	-
30	.	.	.	O	27	punct	0

0	A	a	DT	O	3	det	0
1	voluntary	voluntary	JJ	O	3	amod	-
2	association	association	NN	O	8	nsubj	-
3	or	or	CC	O	3	cc	0
4	union	union	NN	O	3	conj	-
5	is	be	VBZ	O	8	cop	0
6	a	a	DT	O	8	det	0
7	group	group	NN	O	0	ROOT	-
8	of	of	IN	O	10	case	0
9	individuals	individual	NNS	O	8	nmod	0
10	who	who	WP	O	13	nsubj	-
11	voluntarily	voluntarily	RB	O	13	advmod	-
12	enter	enter	VBP	O	10	acl:relcl	-
13	into	into	IN	O	16	case	0
14	an	a	DT	O	16	det	-
15	agreement	agreement	NN	O	13	nmod	0
16	to	to	TO	O	18	mark	-
17	form	form	VB	O	16	acl	0
18	a	a	DT	O	20	det	-
19	body	body	NN	O	18	dobj	0
20	to	to	TO	O	22	mark	-
21	accomplish	accomplish	VB	O	18	advcl	0
22	a	a	DT	O	24	det	0
23	purpose	purpose	NN	O	22	dobj	-
24	.	.	.	O	8	punct	-

0	With	with	IN	O	3	case	0
1	poor	poor	JJ	O	3	amod	0
2	sales	sale	NNS	O	9	nmod	0
3	of	of	IN	O	6	case	-
4	the	the	DT	O	6	det	-
5	A340-200	a340-200	NN	O	3	nmod	0
6	,	,	,	O	9	punct	0
7	Airbus	Airbus	NNP	ORGANIZATION	9	nsubj	0
8	decided	decide	VBD	O	0	ROOT	-
9	to	to	TO	O	11	mark	-
10	use	use	VB	O	9	xcomp	-
11	the	the	DT	O	13	det	0
12	fuselage	fuselage	NN	O	11	dobj	0
13	of	of	IN	O	16	case	-
14	the	the	DT	O	16	det	1
15	A340-200	a340-200	NN	O	13	nmod	0
16	with	with	IN	O	19	case	-
17	the	the	DT	O	19	det	-
18	wings	wing	NNS	O	11	nmod	0
19	and	and	CC	O	19	cc	-
20	engines	engine	NNS	O	19	conj	0
21	of	of	IN	O	24	case	1
22	the	the	DT	O	24	det	0
23	A330-300	a330-300	NN	O	19	nmod	-
24	.	.	.	O	9	punct	0
